你可能已经听说许多故事开始:
You've probably heard many stories that begin:
很久以前,在很远的地方.
"A long, long time ago, in a land far away."
这个也是.
This one does as well.
但我保证,这是个你从来没有听说过的故事.
But I assure you, this is a story you have never heard before.
是关于一个叫弗雷德的男孩.
It's the story of a boy named Fred.
而它这样开始.
And it begins right here.
是时候了.
It's time.
你得用力,亲爱的.
You must push, dear.
没错.
That's it.
没错.再来一次,快点.是的.
That's it. One more time, come on. Yes.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
这是我见过的最肥的孩子.
It's the fattest baby I've ever seen.
上帝.
Good Lord.
他为什么不哭呢?
Why does he not cry?
他说什么?
What did he say?
他十全十美.
He's perfect in every way.
我们叫他什么?
What shall we name him?
我父亲叫尼古拉斯.
My father was called Nicholas.
是的.
Yes.
尼古拉斯.圣诞老人.
Nicholas Claus.
我主尼可拉斯.
My Saint Nicholas.
弗雷德里克.
Frederick.
你愿意来见你弟弟?
Would you like to come and meet your brother?
来了.
Come along now.
fred爱尼古拉斯从他见过他的第一刻起.
Fred loved Nicholas from the first moment he met him.
事实上,那一天,他就给他一个承诺.
In fact, that day, he made him a promise.
我的哥哥世界,尼古拉斯.
I promise to be the best big brother in the whole world, Nicholas.
但弗雷德保证就开始的.
But Fred's promise is just the beginning of his story.
你看,有时候简单的保证...
You see, sometimes it's easier to make a promise...
...是让人.
... than it is to keep one.
该切蛋糕.
Time to cut the cake.
给你,尼古拉斯.我给你做的.
Here you go, Nicholas. I made this for you.
生日快乐.
Happy birthday.
-谢谢你,弗雷德里克.-那很好,弗雷德里克.
- I thank you, Frederick. - That was very nice, Frederick.
尼古拉斯,你去哪儿?
Nicholas, where are you going?
有个可怜的孤儿叫henry的路上.
There's a poor orphan named Henry who lives down the road.
我把我的给他.他需要我的.
I'm bringing all my gifts to him. He needs them more than I.
真漂亮.
That's lovely.
你认为亨利需要日记叫尼古拉斯吗?
Do you really think Henry needs a journal with the name "Nicholas" on the cover?
弗来德利克!,这是他的东西.
Frederick, it's a saintly thing he does.
小圣尼可拉斯.
My little Saint Nicholas.
那么去fred.
And so it went for Fred.
每次他让他骄傲...
Every time he managed to make his parents proud...
弗来德利克!,你看起来不错.
Frederick, don't you look nice.
...尼古拉斯设法让他父母没有了.
... Nicholas managed to make his parents prouder.
门锁着,所以我决定送进烟囱!真有意思!
The door was locked, so I decided to drop down the chimney! What fun!
哦,尼古拉斯.
Oh, Nicholas.
如果门锁着,为什么你不敲门吗?
If the door was locked, why didn't you just knock?
因为他想得不错.
Because he's inventive.
我自己的衣服,妈妈.
I made the outfit myself, Mother.
我不会告诉别人的.
I wouldn't go telling people that.
真的,弗来德利克!,你怎么就不能像你哥哥?
Really, Frederick, why can't you be more like your brother?
我不恨他.他是好意.
I don't wish to hate him. He means well.
我答应做世界上最好的哥哥.
And I promised to be the best big brother in the world.
你是唯一了解我,chirp-chirp了.
You're the only one who understands me, Chirp-Chirp.
弗来德利克!我注意到你喜欢树...
Frederick! I noticed how much you liked the tree...
...所以我们要把这房子里把礼物下面!
...so now we're gonna bring it inside the house and put presents under it!
是不是很棒啊?
Isn't that wonderful?
chirp-chirp没回来.
Chirp-Chirp never returned.
弗雷德里克?
Frederick?
可怜的fred.
Our poor Fred.
是我的吗?
Is this for me?
那个树最后吸管.
That tree was the last straw.
他开始恨他哥哥,他父母...
He began to resent his brother, his parents...
...甚至生命.
... and even his life.
尼古拉斯,你为什么不先打开你的吗?
Nicholas, why don't you open yours first?
旋转它.转!
Spin it. Spin it!
正如很多的孩子...
And like many unhappy children...
你为什么不打开吗?
Why don't you open yours?
...他变得愤怒.
... he became angry.
顽皮的,甚至.
Naughty, even.
我想知道是什么.
I wonder what it is.
怎么了,尼古拉斯?
What's the matter, Nicholas?
没什么.
Nothing.
但是fred变得更糟...
But while Fred grew worse...
...尼古拉斯越来越慷慨和的...
... Nicholas grew more generous and eventually...
...他实现他母亲的预言.
... he fulfilled his mother's prophecy.
在的,他是个圣人.
In manhood, he literally became a saint.
现在,这是一个鲜为人知的圣徒,但当你成为圣人...
Now, it's a little-known rule of sainthood, but when you become a saint...
...你别动,永恒的青春.
... you freeze in time, eternally ageless.
规则适用于死者的圣人和配偶,好.
The rule applies to the family of the saint and the spouses, as well.
现在,你可能已经有了很多的圣人nick.
Now, you probably already have your suspicions of what became of Saint Nick.
世界也知道爱他圣诞老人.
The world grew to know and love him as Santa Claus.
但是我告诉过你,这是个故事fred.
But as I told you before, this is a story about Fred.
然后是弗雷德故事发生在一个时间和地点...
And the next part of Fred's story occurs in a time and place...
...可能更熟悉你.
... that might be a little more familiar to you.
哦,哦,噢!圣诞快乐!人人都爱圣诞节!
Ho, ho, ho! Merry Christmas! Everybody loves Christmas!
你不能把我的电视!我看你在睡觉!
You can't take my television! I watch that in bed!
你疯了吗?
Are you nuts?
你不能和那样的人跑了.你几岁了?
You can't just run up and kick someone like that. How old are you?
-9.-9?
- Nine. - Nine?
你有55-inch等离子体电视房间?
And you have a 55-inch Plasma TV in your room?
圣诞老人给我去年圣诞节.
Santa got it for me for Christmas last year.
那个穿红衣服不是为你的未来.
The guy in the red suit's not looking out for your future.
你会喜欢的.
You're gonna get hooked on that.
我看到了.16万袋吃起来后...
I can see it now. Sixteen thousand bags of Cheetos later...
...你会醒来,你35岁,哭你生活在肥皂.
...you'll wake up, you're 35, crying about your life in front of the soaps.
我帮了你.你出去了,玩耍,交到朋友.
I did you a favor. You get outside, play around, make some friends.
玩踢罐子,做些运动的.
Play kick the can, do some athletic stuff.
上学,你去运动.
Go to school, you're comfortable to play sports.
你有种族的背景?有自尊心的背景?
You have any ethnic in your background? Any ethnicity in your background?
我打赌你,这是美国.你知道我的意思吗?
I bet you do, it's America. You know what I mean?
上大学申请表.
Put it on the application for college.
突然,你有额外的钱.山姆叔叔很不明智.
All of a sudden, you get a little extra money. Uncle Sam's none the wiser.
你的钱,你买辆摩托车.
You take that extra money, you buy a motorcycle.
也许你认识一个学校.那你能怀孩子.
Maybe you meet a guy at school. Then you'll get pregnant with child.
搞定这个家伙,不行,谁在乎?
It works out with the guy, doesn't work out, who cares?
你很幸运有孩子的.
You're blessed to have a kid in your life.
你会运动.你会成为moderate-to-lukewarm学生.
You'll be athletic. You're gonna be a moderate-to-lukewarm student.
你会有孩子在你大学生.
And you're gonna have a child before you graduate college.
你得感谢吗?不是那个穿红衣服的.
Who are you gonna have to thank? Not the guy in the red suit.
但是你的朋友,fred.
But your pal, Fred.
有时会长!嘿,家伙,你有个女孩球鞋.
Sometimes it hurts to grow! Hey, guy, you got a girl that kicks.
那是你或者是因为你用电视的保姆?
Is that from you or is that because you use the TV as a babysitter?
不付账单了!下次我会来接你老婆离开你!
Don't pay your bills again! Next time I'll come and take your wife from you!
等离子体去我家.-分开,确保没有划痕.
Plasma goes to my place. Pack it separately, make sure it doesn't scratch.
哦,哦,噢!圣诞快乐!每个人都喜欢的...
Ho, ho, ho! Merry Christmas! Everybody loves...
抓住它,抓住它,抓住一次.
Catch it, catch it, catch it one time.
来吧,来吧,来吧,一点点.
Come on, come on, come on, just a little bit.
这样,放松点,放松.该死.
That's it, just easy, easy. Damn it.
-换台,伙计?-是你,伙计.
- Mind changing the station for me, pal? - It's your buck, buddy.
你能改变了,拜托?
Can you change that again, please?
来吧,我喜欢那个.好棋.
Come on, I like that one. That's a good one.
你能靠边,拜托?
Can you pull over, please?
-快点,我们还在15街区的了...-把车开过来,拜托.
- Come on, we're still 15 blocks from the... - Just pull the cab over, please.
wanda,你很吸引我.
Wanda, you have never been more attractive to me.
freddie,我在生你的气.不,我很生气.
Freddie, I'm mad at you. No, I'm seriously mad at you.
整整两天了,你不给我打电话.
Two whole days, you don't call me.
我有你跟我们一起住...
I try and have a conversation with you about our moving in together...
...然后消失.-甜心,我没有消失.
...and then you just disappear. - Sweetheart, I did not just disappear.
我发现自己的机会有sheik了.从印度.
I found myself in a business opportunity with a sheik. From India.
一个嘘...没有sheiks印度!
A sh... There aren't any sheiks in India!
别告诉他.我要一个瑜珈撤退.
Don't tell that to this guy. I had to go on a yoga retreat.
但说实话,我气...强壮的.
But to be honest with you, my chi... really strong right now.
freddie,你知道明天是什么吗?
Freddie, do you know what tomorrow is?
-明天?是的.
- Tomorrow? - Yeah.
是的,我知道明天是什么.
Yeah, I know what tomorrow is.
-这是什么?-明天-明天.
- What is it? - Tomorrow is tomorrow.
今天是今天,我们不该浪费互相争吵.
And today is today, and we shouldn't be wasting it arguing with each other.
不,freddie,除此之外,好的.明天有什么意义?
No, Freddie, apart from that, all right. What is the significance of tomorrow?
你说在谈话是今天之后?
What you're referring to in this conversation is the day after today?
是的.-你问我...
- Yes. - You're asking me...
我想说的是它了...
What I'm trying to say is that when it gets to midnight...
...然后是一分钟午夜,明天开始,那是我的生日!
...and then it's one minute past midnight, tomorrow begins, then it is my birthday!
-什么?-哦,不.
- That? - Oh, no.
我知道.生日的,我知道.是的,是的,是的.
I know that. The birthday thing, that I know. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
别假装你知道今天是我的生日...
Don't try and pretend you knew it was my birthday...
...因为我知道你.你不知道.
...because I know you. You didn't know.
-我知道这是你的生日.-你忘了.
- I do know it's your birthday. - You forgot.
我有个惊喜给你的生日但你毁了它.
I have a surprise planned for you for your birthday but you ruined it.
我需要,惊喜.记得我们三年纪念日?
That's what I need, surprises. Remember our three-year anniversary?
你告诉我要温习法语,你暗示埃菲尔铁塔...
You told me to brush up on French, you drop hints about the Eiffel Tower...
...然后你赌博的内河船在印第安纳州.
...and then you took me gambling on a riverboat in Indiana.
法国人都是给你的.
The French thing was to get you off the scent.
问题是我法国书的录像.
The thing about it was that I bought those French books on tape.
我在三个星期.
I studied for three weeks.
这是法国的,那是你的一部分,没有人能夺走.
That French is yours, that's a part of you, no one can take that away.
喝杯咖啡吗?
Can I get you a cup of coffee?
我不能对你发火.
I just can't stay mad at you.
freddie,你能告诉我关于惊喜?
Freddie, will you tell me about the surprise?
如果我告诉你,我不再是个惊喜.
If I tell you, it would no longer be a surprise.
我知道,我知道,但是...
I know, I know, but...
是的,你是对的.你为什么不告诉我,那么.
Yeah, you're right. You shouldn't tell me, then.
你知道吗?
You know what?
我会告诉你的.这不是个惊喜.
I'm gonna tell you about the surprise. It's not a surprise.
你已经知道是什么,那不是意外.
You already know what it is, so it's not a surprise.
这次,在特殊场合的,我会让你知道.
So this time, on this specific occasion, I'll let you know what it is.
-晚餐.是的.
- It's a dinner. - Yeah.
在一个很新热点在叫了...
At a pretty exciting new hot spot here in town called...
...邦塞宫殿.
...Bonsai Palace.
哦,听起来熟悉,邦塞宫殿.
Oh, that sounds familiar, Bonsai Palace.
是的.-你不是编造的?
- Yeah. - You're not making this up?
如果我们去盆景宫殿,会存在?是吗?
If we go to Bonsai Palace, it's gonna exist? It's gonna be there?
当然,是一个地方.想浪漫,我们迷路了.
Absolutely, it's a hot spot. Think romance, and think getting lost.
查理布朗...
Charlie Brown...
...你是我唯一知道的季节就像圣诞节...
... you're the only person I know who can take a wonderful season like Christmas...
...变成一个问题.
... and turn it into a problem.
也许露西是对的.所有的brown的...
Maybe Lucy's right. Of all the Charlie Browns...
伙计,fred.
My man, Fred.
别在跳的尸体.
Don't come in bouncing off the walls.
如果你能过来,放松,是个绅士,你可以进来.
If you can come in here, relaxed and be a gentleman, then you can come in.
-你能做到吗?你要喝奶吗?是的.
- Can you do that? You want some milk? - Yeah.
好的.别和那个频道...
Okay. Don't be playing with the channels...
...然后把录像和跳舞,太累了.
...and putting on videos and dancing, it's exhausting.
好的.
Okay.
你得去沙发?用脚.
Do you gotta go over the couch? With the feet.
脚很脏,沙发很干净.
The feet are dirty, the couch is clean.
-你的脚的.-我错了.
- You put the feet off the thing. - My bad.
-要牛奶吗?-是的,去拿牛奶.
- Do you want the milk? - Yeah, go get that milk.
嘿,fred.我让圣诞老人今年为狗.我会叫他的通心粉.
Yo, Fred. I asked Santa for a puppy this year. I'm gonna name him Macaroni.
我不知道圣诞老人会知道送我礼物了...
I don't know how Santa's gonna know where to bring me my gifts this year...
...因为我不知道我在哪.
...because I don't know where I'll be.
因为你知道有时,如果我奶奶病了...
Because you know how sometimes, if my grandma's sick...
...我待在婶婶家.
...I end up staying over at my aunt's.
大多数时候,我们待在她男朋友的.
Most of the time, we just end up staying over at her boyfriend's.
你怎么想,佛瑞德?认为圣诞老人会找到我?
What you think, Fred? Think Santa'll find me?
-slam,你想过圣诞老人?-没有.
- Slam, you ever thought about Santa? - Not really.
那家伙是个大红西装在飞行因为他所渴望聚光灯.
The guy's in a big red suit flying around because he craves the spotlight.
他是个名声瘾君子.那家伙是个小丑.
He's a fame junkie. The guy's a clown.
他是个自大狂.这是个大骗局的.
He's a megalomaniac. It's all a big shell game.
他喜欢,看着我,我很好.
He presents himself like, "Look at me, I'm so nice."
钱.他有事情发生.
He's getting paid. He's got a whole thing happening.
他们卖更圣诞老人雕像和首饰逃之夭夭了...
Know they sell more Santa statues along with trinkets...
...比他们佛祖吗?
...than they do of Buddha?
哦,大胖小子是在美甲店吗?他这样
Oh, the big fat dude that be in the nail salon? He be like:
不要啦啦队的圣诞老人.想想,注意角度.
Don't be a cheerleader for Santa Claus. Think about it, watch the angles.
不喝他的kool-aid.
Don't drink the Kool-Aid.
-我没有料.-别喝没有料.
- I like Kool-Aid. - Don't drink this Kool-Aid.
你不会问圣诞老人了?
You not gonna ask Santa for nothing?
slam,我也没有慈善的圣诞老人.把双手牛奶.
Slam, I get what I want without charity from Santa. Two hands on the milk.
-两只手.-如果你要喝酒.
- Two hands. - Two hands if you're gonna drink.
我要到一笔利润经济情况的.
I'm about to step into a lucrative business situation right now.
我在工作.我在资产.
I'm working. I'm creating assets.
你知道吗?我要开始新的工作.
You know? I'm starting a new business.
-他妈的什么?-资产.
- A ass what? - Assets.
-那是什么意思?-把你的贫民窟.
- What that mean? - Get your mind out of the gutter.
请,leon,一定是了.
Please, Leon, it's gotta be the spot.
你得全面50,支出按20th了.
You gotta come up with the full 50,000 by the 20th.
我唯一能坚持.人们着我的脖子.
The only way I can hold it. People are breathing down my neck.
我拿到钱了.也许我们不明的...我拿到钱了.
I got the money. Maybe we're not underst... I got the money.
这并不是关于钱.是还本钱.
It's not about the money. It's liquidating the money.
我必须把钱的事情所以我可以倒吧.
I have to get the money in a liquid situation so that I can pour it.
听着,你在美国最大的产业?
Listen, what's the largest growth industry in America?
是赌博,对吗?
It's gambling, right?
这个空间站在现在,三个月后...
This space we're standing in right now, in three months' time...
...将most-traffickedofftrackbetting场外赛马赌博的.
...will be the most-trafficked OTB in the city.
我们在街对面的芝加哥商业交易.
We're across the street from the Chicago Mercantile Exchange.
于是每一天长和商人到街上...
So every day when the market closes and the day traders hit the streets...
...他们会来,leon.是我的一切.拜托.
...this is where they're gonna come, Leon. It means everything to me. Please.
听着,我不想听到任何futzing你,伙计.
Listen, I don't wanna hear no futzing from you, pal.
我需要的22nd了.最.
I need it by the 22nd. The best I can do.
什么.会的...我们会搞定的.
Whatever. It's gonna be fi... We're gonna work it out.
-我想听到你说22nd了.-会很完美.
- I wanna hear you say the 22nd. - It's gonna be perfect.
-22nd完美无缺.-可能是22nd,或者23rd,无论如何.
- 22nd is perfect. - Likely the 22nd, or the 23rd, either way.
22nd了.这是我能做的.就这样.
22nd and that's it. That's the best I can do. And that's it.
不.讨厌的,不过了.但如果是23rd了...
No more. Icky, but done. But if it's the 23rd...
好了.
Done.
-twenty-second了.-2:2了.
- Twenty-second. - Two-two.
-谢谢.-谢谢.
- Thanks. - Thank you.
谢谢.
Thank you.
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
好吧,女士们先生们!
All right, ladies and gentlemen!
这次大家都喜欢的慈善活动,人们帮助!
Step up for everyone's favorite charity, People Help the People!
嘿,抱抱!你漂亮美洲豹.
Hey there, give me a hug! You gorgeous leopard.
谁是女皇丛林?你!
Who's the queen of the jungle? You are!
让我看看能找到什么.哦,我喜欢.来吧,我喜欢你!
Let me see what we got. Oh, I like it. Come on, I like how you do it!
我在报纸上!深入的.
Rock me with some paper! Dig deeper.
还有20.让我看看你有什么.
And another 20. Let me see what you got.
我要两个.什么.祝你圣诞快乐.
I'll take both of them. Whatever. Merry Christmas to you.
嘿,小姐!
Hey, lady!
如果你想救赎,没有军队能给你,唯一能!
If you want salvation, no army can give it to you, only people can!
带你来这里!没错.给我行动.
Bring your action down here! That's it. Give me that action.
-我们只帮助那些人.-你认为你在干什么?
- We only help the people out. - What do you think you're doing?
等我一下.我会解决你.别挤我.
Just give me a second. I'll deal with you in a minute. Don't crowd my action.
然后帮助一些人的.
Then help some of these people out this year.
圣诞快乐.你很美,好.出去.
Merry Christmas. You're beautiful, great. Get out of here.
我不明白你的许可.你需要许可证干这个的.
I don't see your permit. You need a permit to work this street.
好的.我没必要回答你,伙计.我回答的.
Okay. I don't answer to you, buddy. I answer to the people.
-别管闲事,拜托.-救世军是我的!
- Mind your own business, please. - The Salvation Army is my business!
-怎么回事?-这家伙在没有报纸!
- What's going on? - This guy's working without papers!
-他殴打救世军!-我不是骂救世军.
- And he's bashing the Salvation Army! - I'm not bashing the Salvation Army.
我从没被什么.那不是打任何人.不编造谎言.
I never bashed anything. That wasn't bashing anybody. Don't make up lies.
让我看看你的证件,小丑.
Show me your papers, clown.
文件?你的,那个1950s吗?
Papers? What are you from, the 1950s?
看人们帮助人们网上,你会看到照片.
Look up People Help the People on the Internet, you'll see a picture.
你为什么不进入21世纪吗?
Why don't you step into the 21 st century?
好的.叫警察,伙计.
Right. Call the cops, man.
你有个警察!
You got a cop right there!
-哪里?-那边.
- Where? - Right over there.
停下,小偷!
Stop, thief!
有人报警!
Somebody call the cops!
拦住他!-他是个骗子!
- Cut him off! - He's an impostor!
带他出去!
Take his legs out!
-快点!帮帮我们!帮帮我们!-抓住他!
- Come on! Help us out! Help us out! - Get him!
让开!
Get out of the way!
抓住他!
We got him!
-你们找到他!-快点!快点!
- You guys got him! - Come on! Come on!
我们跳舞吧.我们跳舞吧!
Let's dance. Let's dance!
来吧,他不会把我们全部!
Come on, he can't take us all!
只有一个人会离开这,我保证...
Only one man's gonna walk away from this thing, and I promise you...
...这是闪电快伙计那些大黄在他的手.懂吗?
...it'll be the lightning quick dude with the big yellow things in his hands. Dig it?
帽子不错,圣诞老人!
Nice hat, Santa!
wanda,你在吗?
Wanda, are you there?
你能听到我吗?是弗雷德的.
Can you hear me? It's Fred calling.
你现在很重要.你在餐厅?
Kind of important you pick up right now. Are you at the restaurant?
给打个电话,尽快.好吗?
Give a call when you get a chance, as soon as possible. Okay?
希望,我会找你.再见.
Hopefully, I'll talk to you soon. Bye.
是的,她不接电话,是的...
Yeah, she's not picking up the phone, so...
什么事,这是圣诞节.去吧,再打电话.
What the hell, it's Christmas. Go ahead, make another call.
哦,孩子.
Oh, boy.
不,有没有灰色的.它完全白人.
No, there's not even a hint of gray left. It's gone totally white.
亲爱的,你觉得我看起来傻如果我染了?
Honey, you think I'd look silly if I dyed it?
你全发,亲爱的.
You have a nice full head of hair, honey.
这是白人,不过.过早的白人.
It's white, though. Prematurely white.
哦,尼克.你是怎么了.
Oh, Nick. You carry the weight of the world on your shoulders.
我不是压力.
I am not stressed out.
我有很多心事的.
I just got a lot on my mind is all.
你好像很不开心.
You seem upset.
甜心,我们在去年2%的输出限额.
Sweetie, we're 2 percent behind our delivery quota of last year.
去年,我们几乎成功了.要饼干.
And last year, we barely made it. Want cookie.
甜心,你不能吃你的压力.
Sweetie, you cannot keep eating your stress away.
我是说,有点奇怪他们调查我.
I mean, it's a bit odd that they're checking up on me now.
我是说,他们以前从来没派个效率专家.为什么是现在?
I mean, they've never sent an efficiency expert before. Why now?
-尼克?-弗瑞德!
- Nick? - Fred!
-哦,尼克.-怎么样,佛瑞德?
- Oh, Nick. - How's things there, Fred?
上帝,很高兴听到你的声音.怎么样事情和你?
God, it's good hearing your voice. How've things been with you?
哦,嗯,好吧,好.你知道,生意了...
Oh, well, fine, fine. You know, business is crazy...
...但我们肿胀,我们来了.你好,嗯?
...but we're swell, we're swell. How are you, huh?
太好了.我真为你高兴,尼克.
That's great. I'm really happy for you, Nick.
圣诞是起飞.太棒了.
The Christmas thing is taking off. That's awesome.
是的,不是吧.是的.
Yeah, it's catching on. Yeah.
那么,什么,佛瑞德?有什么我能为你做什么?
So, what's up, Fred? Is there anything I can do for you?
如果你真想送我礼物,我猜是你送的...
If you really wanted to send me a gift, I guess it would be okay if you sent...
...5000去警察局密歇根大道上我的名字.
... $5000 to the police station in Michigan Avenue in my name.
5000美元?
Five thousand dollars?
我没事,对了.我不…..我没事.
I'm fine, by the way. I don 't... I'm fine.
-我很好,但你知道,我…..-等一下,fred.
- I'm okay, but so you know, l... - Hold on a second, Fred.
我不知道这是什么...
I don't know what this is about...
...我不行.-听起来他在困境.
...but I know it can't be good. - It sounds like he's in a tough spot.
如果你想为他做点什么...
If you wanna do something for him...
...我知道这很难,但是你需要练习强烈的爱,亲爱的.
...I know it's hard, but you need to practice tough love, honey.
-我是个圣人,甜心.-粗暴的爱.
- I'm a saint, sweetheart. - Tough love.
有点困难我的爱.
Tough love's a little difficult for me.
试试我,宝贝.
Try for me, baby.
-嘿,佛瑞德?-嘿.
- Hey, Fred? - Hey.
那么,5万,密歇根大道警察局...
So, 5 grand, Michigan Avenue Police Station...
...好了.
...done.
-圣诞快乐,fred.-nick,是...我真的很感激,伙计.
- Merry Christmas, Fred. - Nick, that is... I really appreciate it, man.
你知道吗?我要给你一样礼物了.
You know what? I'm gonna give you a gift this year.
是的,我,尼克.我给你10美元,1000圣诞节.
Yeah, I am, Nick. I'm gonna give you $ 10,000 for Christmas.
圣诞快乐.好吧,感觉怎么样?
Merry Christmas. Okay, how's that feel?
那是…..我不明白,不过.我给你5,fred,是的...
That's... I don't understand, though. I'm giving you 5, Fred, so...
你一定会有人想给的...
You gotta be open to someone trying to give...
...得给别人的.
...because it feels good for other people to give.
去吧,给我50美元,1000上5,好吗?
Go ahead, just send me $50,000 on top of the 5, okay?
然后停止呼吸,让我去放大到60.
Then hold your breath, let me go and blow that up into 60.
我给你10美元,1000我们原50美元,1000回来...
Then I'm gonna give you $ 10,000 off the top with the original $50,000 back...
...所以我给你10美元,000,你给我5000美元.
...so that way I gave you $ 10,000, you gave me $5000.
我给你5000美元.圣诞快乐.
I gave you $5000. Merry Christmas.
等等,等等,等等,fred.
Wait, wait, wait a second, Fred.
-五万美圆上了?-什么?什么?
- Fifty thousand dollars on top of the 5? - What? What?
那只是而已.我有了.
That's just icing on the cake. I have a deal going on.
nick,帮我个忙,别把事情复杂化.
Nick, do me a favor, don't make this complicated.
我有.让一个给兄弟圣诞礼物.
I'm in the spirit. Let one brother give another brother a gift for Christmas.
我感觉很棒.让我感觉好吗?
I feel great about it. Let me feel good?
-求你了.-好的.好吧,好的.
- Please. - All right. All right, all right.
fred,好.听着,我会告诉你...
Fred, fine. Look, I'll tell you what...
...我会付5000为了保释你的,好吗?
... I will pay the 5000 for your bail, okay?
但如果你想要的,那你要过来.
But if you want the rest of this, then you're just gonna have to come up here.
-不!-是的!你挣的钱!
- No! - Yes! You earn that money!
我不认为那是个好主意,我和你在一起.
I don't think that's a good idea, me and you to be with each other.
你知道吗?你从没来探望.
You know something? You've never come up here to visit.
一次都没有.
Not even once.
那是什么...?那我要做什么?
What is it exactly...? What would I need to be doing up there?
刮一些,撒在doodads在饼干...
Shave a few reindeer, sprinkle the doodads on the cookies...
...把星星这些地方找不到他们.很简单.
...put the stars up where the little guys can't reach them. It's easy.
我很难把22nd了.我有我的.
I'd have to have a hard out by the 22nd. That's when I have my deal happening.
好的.twenty-second了.
Okay. Twenty-second.
这不是我的了,然后你妈妈偷袭我...
This isn't about me coming up, then you having Mom ambush me...
快点.我不会去找妈妈.
Come on. I'm not gonna go running to Mom.
我不明白为什么你不派50到60我要给你们10.
I have no idea why you won't send 50 so I can blow it into 60 and give you 10.
对不起.我要练习很爱你,伙计.好吗?
I'm sorry. I'm gonna practice tough love on you, buddy. All right?
我现在告诉你...
And I'm telling you right now...
...如果你不同意,我很抱歉,但我不能付保释金了.
...if you do not agree, then I am sorry, but I cannot pay your bail.
wanda,你能让我进去吗?是fred.
Wanda, can you buzz me in? It's Fred.
嘿,甜心,我知道你回来!
Hey, sweetheart, I know you're home!
freddie,回家.我不想跟你说话.回家!
Freddie, go home. I don't wanna talk to you. Go home!
好吧,wanda,我只是想找个机会来解释.
Okay, Wanda, I just wanted to get a chance to come by and explain.
哦,解释?你想解释一下我的生日晚餐?
Oh, explain? You wanna explain to me my romantic surprise birthday dinner?
我在为人民的慈善组织.
I was working for the People Help People charity organization.
我曾在30圣诞老人竟然!
I was chased by 30 Santa Clauses!
闭嘴下去!大家要睡觉!
Shut up down there! People are trying to sleep!
-我告诉你真相.-她不相信你,伙计!所以滚!
- I'm telling you the truth. - She doesn't believe you, pal! So get lost!
嘿,杰瑞・加西亚,我和我的人..你是最.
Hey, Jerry Garcia, I'm having a talk with someone who l... You're the worst.
fred,你回家吧!
Fred, will you go home right this minute!
wanda,有个不幸的情况我得离开今晚.
Wanda, there's this unfortunate business situation I have to leave for tonight.
什么?
You what?
听着,这是生意我跟我兄弟.
Look, this is a business situation that I'm in with my brother.
我们第一次见面的时候,我说,你有个弟弟或妹妹?
When we first met, I said, "Have you got a brother or a sister?"
你说,不,wanda,不!
And you said, "No, Wanda, I don't!"
我有个兄弟...我的母亲和父亲...
I have a bro... I have the same mother and father...
...但是我从不感到有个兄弟.法庭会告诉我我会的.
...but I never felt like I had a brother. The courts would tell me I would.
-不,听我说...-我这种关系!
- No, listen to me... - I am through with this relationship!
-我不会这么做.-我受不了了.
- I'm not through with this. - I can't take it anymore.
-我受不了了!-我能搞定.
- I can't take it! - I can take it.
freddie,我想我要回伦敦.
Freddie, I think I'm gonna go back to London.
祝你和你哥哥,如果他真的存在!
So good luck with your brother, if he even exists!
-祝你好运.我受不了了.-雨伦敦,你不高兴...
- Good luck. I can't take it. - It'll rain in London, you won't be happy...
wanda!
Wanda!
fred,我需要你!
Fred, I need you!
-不是现在,我很急.-假装我父亲.
- Not now, I'm in a hurry. - Pretend to be my father.
-你在说什么?-他在这里.
- What are you talking about? - He's in here.
-你是谁?-我是孩子的父亲.你是谁?
- Who are you? - I'm the boy's father. Who are you?
我们和儿童服务处,先生.我们要把这个小一个称职的家.
We're with Child Services, sir. We're here to remove this minor from an unfit home.
根据我们的记录,他一年前去世了.
According to our records, his father passed away a year ago.
我以为你说你爸爸是...
I thought you said that your dad was...
好吧,过来一下.
All right, come here a second.
你不能指望别人,放纵的.
You can't count on anyone, Slam.
你得自己照顾自己.
You gotta always look out for yourself.
你知道该怎么做,对吗?
And you know how to do that, right?
是的.
Yeah.
我们直说吧.
Let's get something straight.
如果你要等我唱太阳快出来了...
If you're waiting for me to sing " The Sun Will Come Out Tomorrow" on the way...
...你在浪费时间.我们走.
...you're wasting your time. Let's go.
你呢?
Are you Fred?
是的.
Yeah.
我能看到一些,拜托?
Can I see some identification, please?
嗯,很高兴见到你,fred.我叫willie.我是圣诞老人的精灵.
Well, nice to meet you, Fred. My name is Willie. I'm Santa's head elf.
我不知道.
I wouldn't have known that.
只有一个包?只有继续吗?我会的.
So just the one bag? Just the one carry on? I'll get it.
-你确定吗?-是的,是的,我没事.
- Are you sure? - Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
-好吧,我会帮你的...-不,不.我明白了.我明白了.好的.
- Okay, I'll help you get... - No, no. I got it. I got it. Okay.
-我来拿这个.没关系.-我就可以了.
- I'll just grab this here. That's okay. - I could've gotten it.
如果我有更多的机会,我会的.
If I had one more little shot at it, I would've been just fine.
快点.
Come on.
听着,我在这些飞行...
So listen, I'm not so big on all this flying...
哇,好的.
Whoa, okay.
开始我们下降北极.
We'll start our descent to the North Pole.
我们知道你没有选择旅行去北极...
We know you don't have an option traveling to the North Pole...
...但我们很感激你的,我真喜欢对话.
...but we appreciate your business, and I really enjoyed the conversation.
好吧,你要泡的...?
Okay, is this gonna be a steep...?
真的吗?冰球队吗?
Really? The hockey stop?
是的,有个乘客,你不记得了.
Yeah, there's a passenger back here, in case you didn't remember.
哦,对不起.至少你没有吐.
Oh, sorry. Least you didn't throw up.
小心的.嗯,这里.
Watch your step there. Well, here it is.
主街,北极的.
Main Street, North Pole.
漂亮,不是吗?
Pretty, isn't it?
工作间在你后面.
Workshop's behind you.
克劳斯先生?嗨.你好.欢迎来到北极.很高兴你能来.
Mr. Claus? Hi. Hello. Welcome to the North Pole. It's so nice to have you here.
我是圣诞老人的好帮手.
I'm Santa's Little Helper.
抱歉打搅你,但我们得继续圣诞老人的...
I am sorry to rush you, but we have to keep Santa on schedule...
...因为我们是439小时,22分钟,3秒直到c-day了.
...because we are 439 hours, 22 minutes, and 3 seconds until C-Day.
charlene和对数字她一样漂亮.
Charlene's as good with numbers as she is beautiful.
哦,谢谢.谢谢...
Oh, thank you. Thank you...
-威利.-威利!
- Willie. - Willie!
谢谢,威利.
Thank you, Willie.
所以我希望圣诞老人在26秒.
So I'm expecting Santa in 26 seconds.
红是进入一区.重复,红是进入一区.
Big Red is entering Zone One. I repeat, Big Red is entering Zone One.
-过敏.-他有枪!
- Allergies. - He's got a gun!
哦,不,不.
Oh, no, no.
怎么了?住手!
What's happening? Stop it!
-发生什么事了?住手!-不,不,不,孩子们!孩子们!伙计们,放松!
- What's happening? Stop it! - No, no, no, boys! Boys! Boys, easy!
哦,fred.
Oh, Fred.
你疯啦!
That was nuts!
这发生了什么?你不把我当我第一次者...
What is happening here? You don't have ninjas jump me when I first...
-祝贺啊?-对不起,伙计...
- What kind of greeting is that? - Excuse the guys...
...这是在圣诞节,一个紧张的.
...it's the month before Christmas, a tense time.
他们神经兮兮的.他们要确保我的.
They get jumpy. They gotta make sure nothing happens to me.
也许应该发生的.也许我给他们什么.
Maybe something should happen to them. Maybe I give them something.
不会再发生了.他们不会再做了.
It won't happen again. They won't do it again.
-你应该把这些狗.-我抓住你了.我在上面,尽快.
- You gotta put these guys on a leash. - I got you. I'm on top of it, ASAP.
你记得安妮特.说你要安妮特.安妮特.
You remember Annette. Say hey to Annette. Annette.
annette,你没必要去竟然盛装出席我帐户.
Annette, you didn't have to go get all gussied up on my account.
最后在监狱待磨那轻巧而细长的剑机智的.
That last stint in jail has sharpened that rapier wit of yours.
太好了.我在等你我真的不能满足你.
That's great. I'm here for you and I really can't do enough for you.
真的吗?我以为你是来利用你的好心的哥哥.
Really? I thought you were here to take advantage of your well-meaning brother.
哦,哦,好的.
Oh, ho, okay.
家庭在一起.有意思,有意思,有趣.
Family's together again. Fun, fun, fun.
嘿,fred,我已经安排你睡觉.
Hey, Fred, I've already made your sleeping arrangements for you.
我把你和威利.
I have put you with Willie.
嗯,我们到了.
Well, here we are.
哦,小心你的头.进来吧.
Oh, watch your head there. Come on in.
这里.你怎么想?
Here it is. What do you think?
smurfy了.非常smurfy了.
Smurfy. Very Smurfy.
说实话,我家里有客人.
To be honest, I don't get many house guests.
没人睡在双层100年的.
No one's slept in that bunk for 100 years.
晚安,威利.谢谢你邀请我.
Good night, Willie. Thank you for having me.
晚安,fred.
Good night, Fred.
你确定你不觉得这底下?
You sure you wouldn't be more comfortable down here on the bottom?
我想不会太大的区别,威利.
I don't think it's gonna make much of a difference, Willie.
-好的.晚安,fred.-晚安.
- Okay. Night, Fred. - Good night.
威利,实话实说,我不是这种人.
Willie, just for the record, I'm not really a morning person.
嗯,圣诞老人问我给你一个方向都gift-giving过程...
Well, Santa did ask me to give you a full orientation of the gift-giving process...
...所以我们最好赶快过来.
...so we'd better get a move on here.
是,fred,圣诞老人车间.
Here it is, Fred, Santa's Workshop.
就和孩子和一封信.
It all starts with a kid and a letter.
世界各地,孩子写圣诞老人...
All over the world, children are writing to Santa...
...要求他们要什么圣诞节.
... asking for what they want for Christmas.
亲爱的圣诞老人...
Dear Santa...
...我想为圣诞节的自行车...
... all I want for Christmas is an orange bicycle...
...和香蕉了.
... with banana handlebars.
所有的孩子都信到北极邮局...
All the kids ' letters come here to the North Pole Post Office...
...最忙的世界.
... the busiest in the whole world.
一旦解决了,字母直接拿到玩具工厂.
Once they're sorted, the letters come straight to the Toy Factory.
-橙色车给茉莉gordon.-接过来.
- Orange bicycle for Molly Gordon. - Put her through.
每个玩具那孩子要求是手工做的精灵们.
Each and every toy that a child asks for is handmade by the elves.
重要的是要照顾孩子圣诞老人都感觉.
It's important to Santa that every child feels taken care of.
一次的,玩具到包装.
Once built, the toys make their way to Packaging.
终于,在玩具直到圣诞前夜,当他们把.
And finally, the toys are stored until Christmas Eve, when Santa delivers them.
很高兴知道.谢谢,威利.
It's good to know. Thank you, Willie.
来来圣诞老人在np-100.
Here comes "Here Comes Santa Claus" on NP- 100.
哦,你会喜欢这个的.我们有我们自己的dj.
Oh, you're gonna love this. We have our very own DJ.
嘿,唐尼!djdonnie.
Hey, Donnie! DJ Donnie.
嗯,嗯,嗯,是圣谁要冷静在北极.
Well, well, well, it's the saint who puts the chill in the North Pole.
嘿,嘿,dj唐尼!说嘿我大哥,弗雷迪.
Hey, hey, DJ Donnie! Say hey to my big brother, Freddie.
嘿,兄弟fred,我可以,妓女?
Yo, brother Fred, can I get a "Ho, ho"?
不.
No.
你scrooge,你输了.
You Scrooge, you lose.
我们naughty-nice部门.
Our Naughty-Nice Department.
这是钥匙整个过程...
This is the key to the whole process...
...神经的整个行动,fred.
...the nerve center of the entire operation, Fred.
你有10most-naughty吗?
You have a Ten Most-Naughty list?
哦,是的.是的,现在...
Oh, yeah. Yeah, right now...
...我们有johnny罗林中学的新斯科舍.他是占领第一位.
...we got Johnny Rollins in Nova Scotia. He's occupying the number one spot.
上个月他咬他父亲和他的牙医.
Last month he bit his father and his dentist.
但是为什么他咬他们?
But why did he bite them?
嗯,我猜他们有他们的手太接近他.
Well, I assume that they got their hands too close to his mouth.
当然,有时候孩子都不好.
Of course, sometimes kids are both naughty and nice.
所以,我们做一个最近地,走开...
So in that case, we do an up-to-date determination, hence...
...雪的.
...the snow globe.
我告诉你,好吗?
Let me show you how it works, all right?
timmy杰克逊...
Timmy Jackson...
...纽约.
...New York City.
看这个.
Watch this.
你干什么?滚出去!滚出去!
What are you doing? Get out of my room! Get out of my room!
哦,孩子.好吧,这看起来很被刺伤了.
Oh, boy. Okay, that seems pretty cut and dried.
什么,我们不知道发生了什么,什么...?
What, we don't know what happens, what...?
早上好,fred.亲爱的,我能和你谈谈,拜托?
Good morning, Fred. Honey, may I have a word with you, please?
没错.fred,你呆在那里.不要动.
You betcha. Fred, you just stay right there. Don't you move an inch.
我最好查查的瑞典游泳的人.
I better check up on the all-girls Swedish swimming team.
我希望他们淘气!
I'm hoping they're naughty!
-fred是吧.-你觉得呢?
- Fred is really motivated. - You think?
他会有很大帮助.-你还好吗?能和你.
- He's gonna be a big help here. - How you doing? Be working with you.
那个效率专家到15分钟.
The efficiency expert arrives in 15 minutes.
-我们会没事的.-我知道了,我知道.
- We're gonna be fine. - I know it, I know it.
-给我点东西.是的,我会的.
- Give me a little something. - Yes, I will.
我们走.好的.
There we go. Alrighty.
我们去工作.
Let's get you to work.
现在,我会向你解释的,很简单,好吗?
Now, I'm going to explain this to you in very simple terms, okay?
现在,看到那些蓝色档案?我要你检查这些文件,好吗?
Now, see those blue files? I want you to review those files, okay?
如果孩子攻击你的...
If the kid strikes you as naughty...
...砰!告诉他的.
...bam! Stamp him "Naughty."
好吗?但如果他攻击你不错...
All right? But if the kid strikes you as nice...
是的,你告诉他们不错.
Yep, you stamp them "Nice."
我是个小船在方向盘上.是的.
I'm a cog in the wheel. I am.
好,好的.我得赶快,因为我要有人现在,好吗?
Good, all right. I gotta hustle, because I gotta meet somebody right now, okay?
-是,是的,船长.-船长驾到.
- Aye, aye, captain. - Captain's on deck.
-放心,伙计.-邮递!
- Rest assured, my man. - Mail delivery!
-船被介绍安全!-好吧,伙计.
- The ship's getting steered safely! - All right, buddy.
-太好了.这是什么?-是的,好的.
- Great. So this is it? - Yeah, right.
那只是bethesda,马里兰.
That's just Bethesda, Maryland.
好吧,各位.哦,我的天,这是圣诞老人来啦!
All right, everyone. Oh, my goodness, it's "Here Comes Santa Claus!"
你不必旅游直升机,northcutt先生的.
You didn't have to travel by helicopter, Mr. Northcutt.
我会很乐意把雪橇.
I would've happily sent the sleigh.
我讨厌驯鹿.
I despise reindeer.
你安顿好吗?我们有你的房间准备.
Would you like to settle in? We have your room ready.
你小睡一下.
You could take a little nap.
我不睡.
I don't nap.
嗯,听起来会很出色.
Well, that sounds like it's gonna be dandy.
你可以看出图标示116-9c了...
As you can see from the chart labeled 116-9C...
...平均大小的名单也已经长大很多了过去两百年.
...the average size of a child's wish list has grown a lot in the last 200 years.
在1800s,比如,孩子们很少要求更多东西...
In the 1800s, for example, children rarely asked for more than one item...
...通常这些是一个无形的.
...and usually these items were of a intangible nature.
就像家人健康还是结束战争和饥荒.
Something like a family member's health or the end of war or famine.
我记得.试试说的烟囱,嗯?
I remember that. Try fitting that down the chimney, huh?
图345-11b显示今天...
Chart 345-11 B shows that today...
...平均孩子要求15礼物每一封信.
...the average child asks for 15 gifts per letter.
立法的孩子越来越复杂的玩具...
Growing child demands and increasingly complicated toy making...
...让你的工作更每年后面.还不够好.
...are putting your operation further behind each year. It's not good enough.
嗯,现在,我们不是给每个孩子都想要的玩具.
Well, now, we are not here to give every child every toy that they want.
northcutt先生,是圣诞节的感激的我们有.
Mr. Northcutt, part of Christmas is being grateful for the things that we can have.
是的,嗯,如果只是那么简单.-不是?
- Yes, well, if it were only that simple. - It's not?
不.伤心.你看...
No. Sadly. You see...
...董事会的考虑...
...the board is seriously considering...
...你下来.
...shutting you down.
什么?
What?
-这不公平.-就算我们吗?
- That's so unfair. - Shutting us down?
streamlining,的...
Streamlining, consolidating...
...外部采办一个全新的行动建立的...
...outsourcing an entirely new operation based at...
...我知道这很难找你...
...and I know this is gonna be tough for you to hear...
...建立在南极.
...based at the South Pole.
不只是你.我们把牙的孩子,有齿的.
It's not just you. We're putting the tooth fairy on a one child, one tooth system.
你的牙,有巴克,放在枕头下面.
You lose your first tooth, get a buck, put it under the pillow.
然后继续你的生活.这一点...
But then get on with your life. It's getting a bit...
你不觉得吗?还有,我们要把复活节兔子.
Don't you think? Also, we're gonna dump the Easter bunny.
太没道理了.
It just doesn't make any sense anymore.
我是说,复活节兔子和鸡蛋的.
I mean, Easter and bunnies and eggs and all that.
那个协同?不明白.
Where's the synergy? Don't get it.
现在,让下名单上,可以吗?
Now, let's move on to the next item on the list, shall we?
你实际上给那些精灵吗?
How much are you actually feeding those elves?
wandablinkowski,芝加哥,伊利诺伊.
Wanda Blinkowski, Chicago, Illinois.
那个特别的人?
Is that someone special?
是的.那是我女儿,那里.
Yeah. That's my girl, there.
哦,不.我完全给忘了.听着,我有硬币这里.
Oh, no. I totally spaced out. Look, I got a quarter right here.
嗯,对不起,亲爱的,但是2分钟太迟了.
Well, I'm sorry, darling, but you're two minutes too late.
-真的吗?-是的,真的.
- Really? - Yeah, really.
那一定让你感觉不错,人与你争论.
That must make you feel bad, having people argue with you.
是的,嗯,绝对不是最工作.
Yeah, well, it's definitely not the favorite part of my job.
我补偿你?我带你去吃饭.
How about I make it up to you? Let me take you to dinner.
去吃饭吗?
Go to dinner with you?
就当是餐的谈话.
Consider it a meal and sparkling conversation.
不,不行,谢谢,但我不能.
No, I can't. Thank you, but I can't.
总是很痛苦看一个坠机,伙计.
It's always painful to watch a guy crash and burn, my man.
你有男朋友吗?
You have a boyfriend?
不.不,事实上,我没有.
No. No, actually, I don't.
嗯,这是好事.你说什么?
Well, that's a good thing. What do you say?
嗯,我给你一张票.
Well, I'll give you a ticket.
我会给你我的名片.
And I'll give you my card.
好的.很高兴见到你.
Okay. Nice to meet you.
这可能是我收到的票.
This may be the best ticket I ever got.
你要不到30天,你知道吗?
You gotta pay it within 30 days, you know that?
我会在那之前,对吗?
I'll see you before then, right?
爱尔帕索.
El Paso.
好.
Great.
你不会相信这个!再要求圣诞老人来啦!
You're not gonna believe this! Another request for "Here Comes Santa Claus!"
这一次beth会计部.给你!
This time from Beth in Accounting. Here you go!
你开玩笑吗?你开玩笑的圣诞老人吗?
Are you kidding me? Are you kidding me with the "Santa Claus" again?
嘿,dj!
Hey, DJ!
-dj唐尼!-怎么了,弗莱德!
- DJ Donnie! - What up, Fred!
别玩同一首歌的.就像精神折磨.
Stop playing the same song over and over again. It becomes like mental torture.
但是,fred,很上口!
But, Fred, it's so catchy!
上帝.好吧,donnie.这是一首是在的.
God. Okay, Donnie. It's one song that's being played over and over again.
唯一让那是你在同样的歌.
And the only thing that breaks that up is you announcing it's the same song.
很好去玩的.
It would be a nice gesture to play something different.
-我说不!-唐尼,换歌.
- I said no! - Donnie, change the song.
-不!不!-换歌!
- No! No! - Change the song!
你知道吗?我要换歌,那么,给你.
You know what? I'm gonna change the song, then, for you.
你拿的什么?音乐是爱.
What are you getting physical for? Music's about love.
别和我的身体.我们想分享.
Don't get physical with me. We're trying to share.
你干什么?住手.来吧,停下...什么,你要做的?
What are you doing? Stop it. Come on, stop... What, are you gonna do it to me?
唐尼,停下.你就像个训练狗.
Donnie, stop. You're acting like an untrained dog.
冷静.深呼吸.别挥了.你冷静下来好吗?
Get ahold of yourself. Take a breath. Stop swinging at me. Will you calm down?
好吧,你知道吗?我要supernanny你.
Okay, you know what? I'm gonna Supernanny you.
把你的柜子.你不能控制自己.
Put you in the Naughty cabinet. You can't handle yourself.
听我说,冷静下来了.住手.
Listen to me, calm it down a little. Stop it.
说话.说话.
Use your words. Use your words.
我会让你一旦对不起你准备绕过拐角...
I'll let you out once you're sorry and you're ready to turn a corner...
...我们是一个团队,好吗?-别这样!把我的小精灵的屁股!
...and be a team player, okay? - Don't do it! Put my elf foot up your butt!
我来自南方北极?,伙计.
I'm from the south side of the North Pole, man.
-我听到了.让我出去!-跳!跳起来!
- I hear you. Let me out! - Let's heat it up! Let's heat it up!
来吧,我们把它!
Come on, let's loosen it up in here!
你有同样玩了.咱们玩起来!我们去跳舞.
You got the same thing playing all the time. Let's liven it up! Let's get dancing.
让我们兴奋的.我们要一起.
Let's get our blood pumping. Let's make some bad decisions with each other.
快点.
Come on.
别看,宝贝,点火.
Stop looking shy, baby, light it up.
哦,天啊.
Oh, my goodness.
听起来很生气!
It sounds angry!
我知道.
I know.
我喜欢.
I like it.
集合!
Bring it in!
你想过来吗?
You wanna come up here?
你生活在北极...
Your continued existence at the North Pole...
...将决定简单three-strike政策.
...will all be decided on a simple three-strike policy.
熬过圣诞没有三次,我送回来的报告.
Make it through Christmas without three strikes, I send back a positive report.
如果,但是,你三次了...
If, however, you do get three strikes...
...整个行动会永远关闭.
...this entire operation will be shut down permanently.
哦,还有一件事,绝对没人知道为什么我在这里.
Oh, and one more thing, absolutely nobody is to know why I'm here.
尤其是精灵.
Especially the elves.
当然.northcutt先生,精灵非常投入和勤劳的.
Of course. Mr. Northcutt, the elves are extremely dedicated and hardworking.
我确信他们会让你,先生.
I am confident that they will impress you, sir.
哦,哦,天哪.
Ho, ho, holy cow.
住手.住手.停下.
Stop it. Stop it. Stop.
各位,这是northcutt先生的.
Everyone, this is Mr. Northcutt.
他会和我们一起过圣诞.
He'll be with us through Christmas.
请让他欢迎让他观察.
Please make him welcome and let him observe.
回去工作.
Back to work.
他们从没表现的.我保证.
They have never behaved like that before. I assure you.
精灵纪律.
No elf discipline.
显示完全失去控制你的工人.
Showing a complete lack of control over your entire workforce.
这是大事.我很失望.那是一个好球.
That's a biggie. It's disappointing. And that would be strike one.
对不起,我没有你的名字.-哦,是fred.那是我哥哥.
- I'm sorry, I didn't catch your name. - Oh, that's Fred. That's my older brother.
-他是来帮你的.-我不知道你还有个弟弟.
- He's just helping out for the season. - I didn't know you had a brother.
northcutt先生,我应该有人告诉你.威利!
Mr. Northcutt, I should have someone show you around. Willie!
一下,那里,northcutt先生的.
Take a tour, there, Mr. Northcutt.
fred.什么你到底在干什么?
Fred. What in the heck are you doing?
nick,我坦白跟你,dj是个问题.
Nick, let me be completely honest with you here, the DJ is a real problem.
fred,他是精灵那玩的.
Fred, he's an elf that plays records.
nick,他继续演奏老调反复的...
Nick, he continued to play the same song over and over and over and over...
给你.给你.
Got you. Got you.
他决定把手放在我把身体想要伤害我.
He then decided to lay his hands on me and get physical and tried to hurt me.
好吗?现在,我要做个决定的时刻.
Okay? Now, I have a decision to make in that moment.
我想找打?我想英镑精灵的头?
Do I wanna try to get physical? Do I wanna pound this elf's head in?
答案是不.我想他知道怎么感觉不尊重...
The answer to that is no. I want him to know how it feels not to be respected...
...当你在做你的工作.-小点声.小声点.
...when you're trying to do your work. - Just lower your voice. Keep it down.
老实说,如果你决定要惩罚他,我不会生你的气.
And to be honest, if you decide to punish him, I'm not gonna be mad at you.
我不会生你的气.
I'm not gonna be upset with you.
如果你想把锤子看扁他dj手上,做,伙计.
If you wanna bring the hammer down upon his little DJ hands, do it, dude.
好的.好的.那是一个想法.我会坐在这让它滚.
Okay. All right. That's a thought. And I'm gonna sit on that and let it boil.
但我要告诉你,精灵必须保持警觉,现在.
But what I'm trying to tell you is, the elves have got to stay sharp, right now.
非常重要,好吗?
Very important, okay?
我们不能有任何的问题,了,好吗?
We can't have any type of problems, anymore, okay?
我明白了.我们说,兄弟,我知道你从哪儿来的.
I get it. We're two brothers talking now, I know where you're coming from.
才重要.是.
That's all that counts. That's what counts.
现在,你说,不会的...
Now that you said that, it's not gonna happen...
...我会杀了他的.-不,不,不,你不必.
...I'm gonna kill him with kindness. - No, no, no, you don't have to.
爱,的,是你喜欢辐射什么的.
Love, kindness, it's coming off of you like radiation or something.
不,不,不.你会在你的.
No, no, no. You're gonna stay at your station.
好的.
Right.
-支撑,对吗?-最温和的航行.
- Smooth sailing, right? - The smoothest sailing.
freddie,我很高兴你带我去吃晚饭.
Freddie, I am so glad you took my invitation for dinner.
我很高兴我们能出去像兄弟一样.
I'm excited we're gonna be able to hang out as brothers.
-进餐,对吗?-当然.
- Break bread, right? - Absolutely.
我要一个.
I want one.
-尼克!nick!-哦,孩子.什么?
- Nick! Nick! - Oh, boy. What?
-尼克!-什么?
- Nick! - What?
-nick,过来.-好吧,好的.
- Nick, come here. - Okay, okay.
到底是妈妈在吗?
What the heck is Mom doing in the house?
我要你说实话,她知道我在这儿吗?
I want you to be honest, does she know I'm here?
说我疯了,但我妈妈来探望我度假每年.
Call me crazy, but my mom comes and visits me for the holidays every year.
我不会在那里,nick,因为我不去见妈妈...
I'm not going in there, Nick, because I don't visit with Mom...
...我没有理由的.-真不错,如果,一次...
...and I don't for good reason. - It would be really nice, if, for once...
...是很冷静你过来吃晚饭.
...things were nice and calm and you just dropped by for dinner.
-不是有争议的.我不去.-哦,哦,哦,我不会听我的.
- This isn't even debatable. I'm not going. - Ho, ho, ho, I'm not gonna listen to no.
这本书,是弗雷德去吃晚饭?一页页读下去...
There's a book, Does Fred Go to Dinner? Flip through the pages...
...最后的,fred不去吃饭.最后.
...and last page, Fred does not go to dinner. The End.
续集,知道这叫什么吗?叮当,是谁?为什么,是fred.
The sequel, know what it's called? Ding-dong, Who 's There? Why, it's Fred.
-我不去.-南瓜饼.快点.
- I'm not going. - Pumpkin pie. Come on.
明白了.我不会吃!
Get it through your head. I am not going to dinner!
你好,我希望没有打扰你们...
Hello, I hope I'm not intruding...
...但我遇到了你父母,他们邀请我吃晚餐.
...but I ran into your parents, and they invited me to dinner.
哦,不,不,是的,欢迎,欢迎.
Oh, no, no, yeah, welcome, welcome.
-我们到了.-,弗来德利克!,你还好吗?
- Here we are. - So, Frederick, how have you been?
-我很好,妈妈.我一直很好.-太好了.
- I've been good, Ma. I've been real good. - That's nice.
我会告诉你,fred做一个极好的工作...
I'll tell you, Fred has been doing a bang-up job...
...到naughty-nice部门.
...down in the Naughty-Nice Department.
我一直在做一个极好的工作.
I wouldn't say I've been doing a bang-up job.
我有并发症打的斑点...
I had complications and hit rough spots...
...但是我已经尽力了.-哦,是的,不,不,不...
...but I'm doing the best I can. - Oh, yeah, no, no, no...
...你证明是很难的.
...you are proving to be one very hard worker.
嗯,我想他可能很难工人,考虑到.
Well, I would imagine he's probably a very hard worker, considering.
考虑什么?
Considering what?
还没时间的宴会.
Considering that you didn't have the time to come to our anniversary party.
-给我们一个派对.-弗瑞德送的礼物,不过.
- Your brother gave us quite a shindig. - Fred sent a lovely gift, though.
来吧,现在,那按摩椅子,看起来非常,非常昂贵.
Come on, now, that massage chair, that looked very, very expensive.
是的,的确是.
Yes, I'm sure it was.
-发生什么事了?-你什么意思?
- What's happening? - What do you mean?
-我不知道...怎么了?-没事发生.
- I don't see... What's happening? - Nothing's happening.
好的.
Okay.
-哦,你还好吗?-喜欢信用卡来的.
- Oh, you all right? - Even enjoyed the card that came with it.
你还记得你写的,弗雷德里克?
Do you remember what you wrote on the card, Frederick?
嗯,是这样的:
Let's see, was it something like:
周年纪念快乐,我希望你在吗?
"Happy anniversary, I hope you choke on your meal"?
现在你很傻.
Now you're just being silly.
有汁的,亲爱的.土豆非常干燥.
Have some gravy, darling. The potatoes are awfully dry.
phyllis,我希望你不会说,尼古拉需要减肥.
Phyllis, I wish you wouldn't do that, because Nicholas needs to lose weight.
他很好!
He's perfect!
你会飞的一个晚上.
You're looking at a man who can fly around the world in a single night.
-难以置信!-好吧,妈妈.
- That's unbelievable! - Okay, Mom.
你知道,我不能克服的,尼古拉斯.我只是...你让我吃惊.
You know, I can never get over that, Nicholas. I just... You amaze me.
-是不是很棒啊?-我觉得好极了.
- Isn't it amazing? - I think it's absolutely amazing.
认为他能飞到很多房子的...
To think that he can fly around to a million houses in one night...
...非法闯入,看着孩子...
...breaking and entering, staring at little children...
...吃小孩子饼.
...eat the little kids' cookies and stuff.
那是个杰出的事件.我完全疯了...
That's a phenomenal occurrence. And I get jacked out of my mind...
...只想着那些法律被破坏.你们不觉得吗?
...just thinking about all those laws being broken. Don't you guys feel it?
弗来德利克!,你为什么这么沮丧?
Frederick, why are you so upset?
哦,来吧,妈妈.不…..
Oh, come on, Mom. Don't...
我希望你更像你哥哥.
I just wish you were a little more like your brother.
好.好的.
Great. Okay.
我有预感我会舒服多回我的小屋...
I have a feeling I'd be much more comfortable back in my little hut...
...和"和奶昔.
...with some Hot Pockets and a milkshake.
快点.别这样.fred.
Come on. Don't be like that. Fred.
我的家庭会议.我找到这个...
I just love meeting people's families. I find it so...
...暴露了.
...revealing.
晚安,多霜!明天见!
Night, Frosty! See you tomorrow!
-弗瑞德!好极了!进来,我的朋友.-你好,威利?
- Fred! Terrific! Come on in, my friend. - How are you, Willie?
我很好!拉大便了.
I'm great! Pull up a stool.
嘿,蛋酒给fred,上进.
Hey, eggnog for Fred, Frosty.
-当然,他们正赶来.-要双份的.
- Sure, they're on the way. - Make it a double.
谢谢.
Thank you.
嘿,fred.
Hey, Fred.
-莎莉.是的.
- Charlene. - Yeah.
你知道,你看到这些人了...
You know, you see these people after work...
...我甚至不认识他们.你知道,比如,哦,当然.沙琳.
...and I don't even recognize them. You know, like, "Oh, of course. Charlene."
是的.-晚安,fred.
- Yeah. - Good night, Fred.
-晚安,沙琳.-晚安...
- Good night, Charlene. - Good night...
-威利.-威利.
- Willie. - Willie.
fred,我不…..我不…..
Fred, I don't... I don't...
我不明白,fred.
I don't understand, Fred.
她不记得我的名字?
She doesn't remember my name?
怎么了,佛瑞德?是啊...?是我,不是吗?
What is it, Fred? Is it...? It's me, isn't it?
你可以告诉我,fred,没关系.因为你是我的朋友.
You can tell me, Fred, it's okay. Because you're my friend.
就是这样...她觉得我是个怪人.
It's just that... She thinks I'm a freak.
我爱她.我爱她.
I love her. I love her.
威利,瞧.你想笑.你是很多乐子的.
Willie, now look. You love to laugh. You're a lot of fun to be around.
fred,我开玩笑的.
Fred, I can't even tell a joke.
我说最后一道的.恐怕都会听.
I say the last line first. I'm afraid everyone's gonna stop listening.
这很简单.
This thing is very easy.
让她知道你准备好玩,你不会道歉.
Let her know that you're ready for fun, and you are not gonna apologize for it.
你知道,去年在after-christmas派对...
You know, at last year's after-Christmas party...
...我请她跳舞.
...I almost asked her to dance.
我知道我不会跳舞.
Then I remembered I can't dance.
-呢.-什么?
- Yet. - What?
不能跳舞.
Can't dance yet.
fred.真荒谬.
Fred. I feel ridiculous.
我不知道怎么跳舞.我不知道舞步.
I don't know how to dance. I don't know the steps.
这让我很不舒服.
This is very uncomfortable for me.
快点.离开你一会儿.进入你的身体!
Come on. Get out of your head for a second. Get into your body!
好吧,看,我不会那么做的.我不可能.
Okay, see, I'm not gonna do that. I can't actually do that.
我们不再跟这个,我们要找的...
We're no longer talking with this, we're gonna talk with...
带.来了.
Bring it. Bring it right now.
把绿色天那你把它给我.
Bring all that green goodness that you have on and bring it right up on me.
来吧,这个漂亮的绿天使.现在,手放在这里.
Come on, this beautiful green angel. Now, put one hand here.
好.把另一把了.来吧,握的.别害羞.
Great. Put another hand here. Come on, grip it. Don't be shy.
我们要做的就是有点宝贝思维.
All we're gonna do is a little bit of a baby sway.
这样,我的摇滚去.只是放松.
That's it, just a gentle rock back and forth. Just easy.
现在,有短的,这很好...
Now, you got short arms, which is good...
...因为你得靠近.
...because it means you gotta get close.
快点,这个大拖轮上岸了.起锚.
So go ahead, pull this big tugboat to shore. Anchors aweigh.
没错.好吧,现在,接下来你把手放在背后.
That's it. Okay, now, the next thing you do is put your hand on my back.
那不是我,但这是有点调皮.
That's not my back, but it is a little bit naughty.
我喜欢你想去的地方,但是为了这个目的,让我们保持专业.
I like where you're headed, but for these purposes, let's just keep it professional.
-fred.-现在,记住,威利...
- Fred. - Now, remember, Willie...
...跳舞,跳舞不是,对吗?
...dancing is not about dancing, right?
关于连接的.现在,看着我的眼睛.
It's about connecting. Now, look me in the eye.
好.现在,如果我是个女孩,我起鸡皮疙瘩你带来了.
Great. Now, if I was a girl, I'd get goose bumps with what you just brought.
其他的跳舞是完美的桥梁吻.
The other great thing about dancing is it's the perfect bridge to a kiss.
你所要做的就是乐趣,我知道我会开心的...
So all you gotta do is have fun, let me know I can have fun...
...当时机合适,当你开始行动.
...and then when the time's right, that's when you make your move.
让我兴奋了.开始感觉到.
Get my blood pumping. Start to feel it.
让你兴奋!
Get your blood pumping!
让我们兴奋.开始吧.
Let's get excited. Let's make it happen.
来吧,大人物.然后告诉我你不知道.
Come on, big guy. Turn around and show me what you don't know.
没错.好的.这看.继续,宝贝.
That's it. Okay. That's one way to look at it. Keep moving it, baby.
没错.保持开机.没有规则.我喜欢.你让它发生.
That's it. Keep rolling. There's no rules. I like it. You're making it happen.
你在跳舞.没关系,不好,好!
You're dancing. That's okay, and it's not okay, and it's okay!
感觉!跟着它.
Feel it! Stay with it.
风的.我喜欢!热的.加油!坚持住,哥哥!
Wind it up. I like it! Heat it up. Work it harder! Stay with it, brother!
哦,我忘了我的手套.
Oh, I forgot my gloves.
没关系.起来平静地.
It's okay. Just get up calmly.
没关系...
That's all right...
威利!
Willie!
你摔倒了,没什么大不了的.
So you fell down, big deal.
fred,不是每个人都掉在他的脸上.
Fred, not everybody falls down on his face in front of the girl he loves.
我看起来像个白痴那里.
I looked like a total idiot out there.
我不会露面了?太荒谬了.
How am I ever gonna be seen in public again? It's ridiculous.
谢天谢地blitzen不觉得他第一次学会飞行.
Thank goodness Blitzen didn't feel that way the first time he learned how to fly.
当blitzen学会f…..?我知道这个故事吗?
When Blitzen learned to f...? Why don't I know this story?
哦,这样,威利.每个人都知道这个故事.
Oh, come off it, Willie. Everyone knows this story.
-blitzen学会飞行吗?他脸上.
- When Blitzen learned to fly? - He fell on his face.
是吗?-他会试图去了...是的.
- He did? - He'd try and take a run... Yeah.
他跑他摔他的脸.
He'd run and he'd fall flat on his face.
但他自己和他会继续努力.
But he picked himself up and he'd keep trying.
最终,他想他飞起来了.
And eventually, he stopped thinking and he flew.
-是常识的.-fred,快点.
- It's common knowledge. - Fred, come on.
-是真的.-我不是blitzen,不过.我不是blitzen.
- It's true. - I'm not Blitzen, though. I'm no Blitzen.
嗯,我同意你,威利.
Well, I disagree with you, Willie.
我知道你在你的blitzen.
I know you got more Blitzen in you than you realize.
爱情很复杂.
Love is so complicated.
是的,不.
Yeah, can be.
好痛.
It hurts.
我为你骄傲,威利.
I'm proud of you, Willie.
现在,晚安.
Now, good night.
晚安,fred.
Good night, Fred.
哦,fred.哦,哪里,哦,哪儿都不信吗?
Oh, Fred. Oh, where, oh, where did all the kids' letters go?
哦,不是很好吗?露西要做饭了.
Oh, isn't that sweet? Lucy wants a cooking set.
嗯,这是你做意大利面,亲爱的.这只是个开始.
Well, here's how you make pasta, darling. There's a start.
哦,小基南亚当斯要自行车圣诞节.
Oh, little Keenan Adams wants a bike for Christmas.
嗯,基南,我猜你会坐公车上学的.
Well, Keenan, I guess you'll be taking the bus to school from now on.
哦,freddie,freddie,你已经非常,非常调皮.
Oh, Freddie, Freddie, you have been so very, very naughty.
我没带任何文件出去.我不要这个了.
I didn't take any of the files out of the room. I never got to the S's.
fred,我不需要告诉你很重要的文件了.
Fred, I don't need to tell you how very important these files are.
没有,我们不知道孩子们的.
Without them, we have no idea what the children want.
或者他们已经盯上还是不错的.
Or whether they've been marked Naughty or Nice.
这是你的责任,当然,记录的.
And it was your responsibility, of course, to keep track of them.
我告诉你,我知道我…..我没带钱...怎么了?
I just told you, I would know if l... I didn't take any... What is going on here?
你站在那儿评判我胳膊折了?
And why are you standing there judging me with your arms folded?
我不是在评判你,我很紧张.
I'm not judging you, I'm nervous.
我也很紧张我并非善类.谁最祈求示威.
I'd be nervous too if I was up to no good. Doth who protests the most.
-你能相信吗?-好的.快点.
- Can you believe this guy? - Okay. Come on.
-我看着你,鲍勃.-是吗?什么,大家伙.
- I got my eye on you, Bob. - Yeah? Anytime, big fella.
bob,安静.
Bob, settle down.
你想说一个精灵,你必须像精灵.
You wanna talk like an elf, you have to act like an elf.
-很容易找到.-谈谈.
- I'm easy to find. - Big talk.
他比你大到,鲍勃.
He's got a bigger reach than you, Bob.
-麻烦?-不,不,不.
- Trouble? - No, no, no.
没有?没人在威斯康星州会得到礼物了!
No? Nobody in Wisconsin's gonna get any gifts this year!
哦,我,我的.那些可怜的孩子.
Oh, my, my. Those poor children.
你没有后备的?
You don't have any backup records?
嗯,我们从来没有这样的.
Well, we've never had something like this happen.
我肯定他们会出现.我是说,毕竟,他们可能了?
I'm sure that they'll turn up. I mean, after all, where could they have possibly gone?
失败的管理后援.
Failure to administrate backup records.
那两好球.
That would be strike two.
听着,这可能是我...
Look, this is probably none of my business...
...但我有点担心fred.
...but I'm a little concerned about Fred.
嗯,我感谢你的关心,northcutt先生,但他很好.
Well, I appreciate your concern, Mr. Northcutt, but he is fine.
我见过这种东西.小谎言...
It's just that I've seen these kind of things before. The little lies...
...闪光愤怒的.
...flashes of anger.
不,我可以向你保证,他没事.
No, I can assure you, he's fine.
嗯,不过可能会更糟,圣诞老人.
Well, but it could get so much worse, Santa.
告诉我,他要大的钱吗?
Tell me, has he asked for large sums of money recently?
什么麻烦?
And what about trouble?
他进了问题吗?
Has he gotten into trouble with the law?
为什么,是的,northcutt先生,是的,他.
Why, yes, Mr. Northcutt, yes, he has.
当然.他是为了帮助.
Of course. He's crying out for help.
如果没有人去帮他,为什么...
And if someone doesn't step in and help him, why...
...我会的.
...I'm afraid it's gonna get ugly.
嗯,我能怎么办,northcutt先生吗?
Well, what can I do, Mr. Northcutt?
我有个想法.但你不会喜欢的.
I did have a thought. But Fred's not going to like it.
什么样的派对你兄弟吗?
What kind of party are you dudes throwing?
航空!航空邮件给我!让我们兴奋!
Airmail it! Airmail it to me right now! Let's get jacked up!
你怎么了,疯了?我觉得pattyhearst!我只是绑架,nick!
What are you, nuts? I feel like Patty Hearst! I was just abducted, Nick!
你要付钱的...
You're gonna have to pay something...
...为那伤害我有我的内心.
...to make up for the hurt I have inside of me.
不会的.我有个律师有元音的姓,尼克.
It's not gonna be cheap. I got a lawyer that's got vowels in his last name, Nick.
他会联系你,让你伤害我的人!
He's gonna contact you and make you feel the hurt I feel from your handlers!
弗来德利克!我们正在一家人了.
Frederick! We're having a family intervention.
你的行为已经接受.
Your behavior has been unacceptable.
-wanda,嗨.-嗨.你还好吗?
- Wanda, hi. - Hi. You all right?
我很好.我很好.你怎么样?
I'm doing terrific. I'm doing great. How've you been?
你知道,我很好.是的,我一直在和...
You know, I've been all right. Yeah, I've been working and...
太棒了.是对人做他们做的.
That's awesome. Work is really good for someone to do when they're doing stuff.
我一直在工作,也,对了.也为我的生活.
I've been working a lot, too, by the way. And also fighting for my life.
我弟弟是圣诞老人.
My brother's Santa Claus.
是的,是的.我可以...我知道.
Yeah, yeah. I can... I can see that.
有点不同.
It's a little different.
是的,整件事是有点不寻常.
Yeah, the whole thing's been a little bit unusual.
fred,你哥哥的人我们想帮你.
Fred, your brother has flown someone in we think can help you.
-这是goldfarb了.-你好.
- This is Dr. Goldfarb. - Hello.
你行为异常要太多压力了.
Your erratic behavior is putting too much stress on your brother.
妈妈,拜托,好吧,我没紧张的.
Mom, for Pete's sake, okay, I'm not stressed out about it.
-尼克!你会崩溃的.-我不是.
- Nick! You're falling apart. - I am not.
是的,你.你处境超重.
Yes, you are. You're dangerously overweight.
他不是!
He is not!
你不知道你儿子过去!
You have no idea what your son is going through!
-好的.-他是个可怕的衣橱.
- Okay. - He is a terrible closet eater.
他已经胃酸逆流而睡眠的.
He has developed acid reflux and sleep apnea.
-我打鼾.我是说,人们打鼾.-是他的...
- I snore. I mean, people snore. - It is keeping him up all night...
...这会影响他的健康,还有其他方面的婚姻.
...and it's affecting his health, not to mention other aspects of our marriage.
哦,哦,哦,安妮特.
Oh, ho, ho, Annette.
他在时间上吗?
He's having a tough time getting off the ground?
我只是说.
I'm just saying.
请,咱们别拐弯抹角了.
Please, let's just cut to the chase.
很简单,总是一样,fred.
It's simple, it's always the same thing with you, Fred.
-你惹麻烦.-亲爱的...
- You cause problems. - Sweetie...
然后你借口...
And then you make excuses...
...比如,你知道,你是关心别人.
...like, you know, you're looking out for someone else.
自从小时候.
Ever since he was a little boy.
如果我说会更好.freddie,那叫你做什么.
I couldn't have said it any better. Freddie, that is what you do.
太好了.帮我个忙,拜托.你为什么不离开这?
That's great. Do me a favor, please. Why don't you just stay out of this?
嗯,我是在干涉.你问我.
Well, I came for the intervention. Your family asked me.
你没有和一个人忘记堵他计吗?
Don't you have a date with a guy who forgot to plug his meter?
你在监视我吗?
Have you been spying on me?
是的.-你有其他事情要做?
- Yes. - You got nothing better to do?
-我不喜欢我看到的.-如果你监视我的...
- I don't like what I saw. - If you spied on me properly...
...你知道我没和他.
...you would know I didn't end up going out with that guy.
这么说你.这不是漂亮的角色...
Let me just say this to you. It is not flattering on your character...
...你那个有liver-spotted手.
...to see you with a man who's got liver-spotted hands.
这是一个很弱的选择.那样会让你显得弱势.
It's a very weak choice. It makes you look weak.
听着,我可以告诉你你的问题.
Look, I can tell you what your problem is.
你不想让别人喜欢你因为你不认为你值得爱.
You won't let anybody love you because you don't think you're worth loving.
出庭作证...
If it pleases the court...
...你的老绅士问你约会?
...did you have an older gentleman ask you out on a date?
是的,但那不是重点!我没看到他了!
Yes, but that's not the point! I didn't see him again!
-她是个约会男人.-你和谁好了.
- Then she's a dater. - You push and fix on one thing.
别再约会.放下电话.
Then stop dating. Put down the phone.
没错.我受够了.
That's it. I've had enough.
对不起,圣诞老人先生.很高兴到北极...
Excuse me, Mr. Santa Claus. It's been very pleasant to come to the North Pole...
...还有,是的.
...and, yeah.
去约会.也许侥幸精灵了.
Go find a date. Maybe get lucky with an elf on the way out.
祝你好运.希望一切顺利.
Good luck. Hope it goes well.
嗯,有很多槲寄生外面,你应该感到兴奋的.
Well, there's a lot of mistletoe out there, so you should be psyched.
fred.
Fred.
我想我们的进展.
I think we're making some real progress.
你知道好消息是什么吗?明天是最后一天.
You wanna know what the good news is about all of this? Tomorrow's my last day.
我们不需要治疗.
We don't have to have therapy.
找人在生活中.我们没这种问题.
It's for people who want to be in each other's lives. We don't have that problem.
我会完成我的工作,我会永远.
I'm gonna finish my job, I'll be out of your lives forever.
晚安.
Nice night.
迷路,家伙.
Get lost, guy.
圣诞老人是兄弟,那一定很累了.
Santa Claus' brother, that must be a tough beat.
我弟弟是个医生.我从来没听说过.
My brother's a doctor. I never hear the end of it.
一半的时间,我觉得我根本不存在.
Half the time, I feel like I don't even exist.
和你的家人对你.
And the way your whole family treats you.
你的故事,伙计?
What's your story, man?
什么?
Excuse me?
听着,你想对我没用.
Look, whatever you're trying to do with me here's not gonna work.
嗯,告诉我吗?
Well, what exactly am I trying?
我不知道你在做什么,但真正的你...
I don't know what it is you're into, but something's real creepy about you...
...自从你来...
...and ever since you got here...
...我哥哥有点紧张.
...my brother's been getting a little bit nervous.
太好了.
That's wonderful.
是啊?
What is wonderful?
你感兴趣你哥哥的功用.
You take an interest in your brother's well-being.
当然.我确定他也一样保护你.
Of course you do. I'm sure he does the same for you.
-克莱德...-你见过树...
- Clyde... - You ever seen a tree...
...它的阴影里另一棵树?
...that grows in the shadow of another tree?
好瘦和畸形只是弯曲和扭曲了...
It's all puny and misshapen because it's just bending and twisting...
...在他们有阳光.
...trying so desperately to get some sunlight.
如果有人把几个英尺的大树...
If somebody just cut off a few feet of that big tree...
...小树会长大的.
...that little tree could grow up strong.
但,那不是生活在,对吗?
But no, that's not the way life works, right?
他们都喜欢那树,对吗?他们都为那个.
They all love that big tree, right? They're all proud of that one.
他们讨厌的小旁边.
They hate the crap out of the little one next to it.
小树拒绝长大的.
The little tree that refuses to grow right.
你知道吗?直到有人过来切下来大树...
And you know what? Till somebody comes along and cuts down that big tree...
...那是不会有光.有光.
...that little tree is never gonna get any light. Any light.
对不起.我不知道哪里来的.
I'm sorry. I don't know where that came from.
圣诞节.
Christmas.
有个愉快的晚上.
Have a nice night.
那是什么?
What the hell was that?
像个孩子就在第一最下流的地方.
Looks like a new kid just took over the number one Most Naughty spot.
放纵的?
Slam?
samuel她,芝加哥,伊利诺伊.
Samuel Gibbons, Chicago, Illinois.
你问的圣诞老人?
What are you asking Santa for?
-家庭.-我想要个家.
- A family. - I'm asking for a family too.
圣诞老人不带你们家庭.圣诞老人是个小丑.
Santa's not bringing y'all families. Santa Claus is a clown.
他是个名声瘾君子.
He's a fame junkie.
他在红衣服...
He puts on a big red suit...
...和着镇上有驯鹿.
...and rides around the town with reindeer.
因为男人的注意.
It's because the man is desperate for attention.
他需要和聚光灯.
The dude needs to be in the spotlight.
还有圣诞老人雕像世界比佛.这是个骗局的.
There's more Santa statues in the world than Buddha. It's a shell game.
你们喝的kool-aid,傻瓜!
Y'all drank all the Kool-Aid, fools!
你知道你不能收养了因为你!
You just know you're never getting adopted because you're mean!
-住手!你会惹麻烦!-放开我!滚开!
- Break it up! You're gonna get in trouble! - Get off me! Get off!
-住手!分开!-滚开!
- Break it up! Break it up! - Get off!
有人会惹麻烦!
Somebody's gonna get in trouble!
我不在乎.我要猛!
I don 't care. I'm Slam!
圣诞老人,我数三下.
Santa, I ran the numbers three times.
是的.
Yeah.
charlene,提任何人.
Charlene, mention this to no one.
-特别是克莱德northcutt了.是的,先生.
- Especially Clyde Northcutt. - Yes, sir.
弗莱德!
Fred!
你到底做了什么?
What the blazes have you done?
你每淘气的孩子好!
You marked every naughty child as nice!
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
-孩子是我的.-啊,弗莱德!
- None of the kids seemed naughty to me. - Good grief, Fred!
你真的从来没有看到死亡的,你呢?
You really never see the ramifications of anything, do you?
我们不会和礼物只有三天了.
We literally cannot make enough presents with only three days left.
我们不能把这些礼物!
We cannot deliver all of those presents!
你看到了吗?结束了.恭喜,弗莱德!
Do you see? It's over. Congratulations, Fred!
你成本圣诞节整个星球!各位!
You've cost Christmas for the whole planet! Everybody!
立陶宛,到处都是在非洲,整件事!
Lithuania, everywhere in Africa, the whole thing!
好了!
Right down the crapper!
责备我,对吗?都是我的错.多方便.
Blame it all on me, right? It's all my fault. How convenient.
annette对你.妈妈对你!
Annette was right about you. Mom was right about you!
你知道,救我!
You know what, save it!
也许你该看看自己的!
Maybe you should look at your own self for a change!
你把你的脸塞姜饼!胖子!
You just keep stuffing your face with gingerbread! Fat boy!
你slick-talking,fast-talking!
You slick-talking, fast-talking punk!
你知道我和一个体重问题了,弗莱德!这并不好笑!
You know I've been battling a weight problem for years, Fred! That is not funny!
你知道吗?你可以把它,雷鸣肌肉!
You know what? You can shove it, Thunder Thighs!
我已经厌倦了.这个小了点光.
I'm sick of it. This little tree's gonna get some light.
这会把大树!
This tree's gonna chop that big tree down!
我没有要你虐待!
I don't have to take your abuse!
nick,我不能失去你我!
Nick, I couldn't miss you if I tried!
我不能失去你我因为你太胖了!
I couldn't miss you if I tried because you're so fat!
你像个女孩,像个大,皮革jacket-wearing女孩.
You throw like a girl, like a big, leather jacket-wearing girl.
来吧,尼克.
Come on, Nick.
来吧,胖子!
Come on, fat boy!
你今天去上班?你呢?
How'd you get to work today? You roll?
你怎么在这儿?你偷个雪橇一些小孩?
How'd you get here? Did you steal a sled from some little kid?
快点!
Come on!
晚安,亲爱的王子.
Good night, sweet prince.
不带个雪上汽车和一个战斗,nick!
Don't bring a snowmobile to a snowball fight, Nick!
你要我过去吗?你要我过去吗?
You gonna run me over? Are you gonna run me over?
我从没想到过.
I never realized it before.
你恨我.
You hate me.
我不恨你,尼克.
I don't hate you, Nick.
我希望你没有出生.
I just wish you were never born.
是的.
Yeah.
克莱德northcutt不是人类的资源,fred.
Clyde Northcutt is not from Human Resources, Fred.
他是个效率专家.
He's an efficiency expert.
他是从这里打我.
And he is one strike away from shutting me down.
永久的.
Permanently.
嗯,希望你满意自己,fred.
Well, I hope you're happy with yourself, Fred.
听着,annette,我要我的钱.说到做到的.
Look, Annette, I want my money. A deal's a deal.
是的.
Yeah.
个人,我不认为你值得一分钱.
Personally, I don't think you deserve a cent.
他想给你这个的.
He wanted you to have this too.
圣诞快乐,fred.
Merry Christmas, Fred.
我们走,威利.
Let's go, Willie.
嗯,好.
Well, well.
northcutt先生的.
Mr. Northcutt.
你想见我,先生.
You wanted to see me, sir.
是的,是的.
Yes, I did.
把馅饼从今天早fred,拜托.
Bring up Fred Claus from earlier today, please.
嗯,现在,我们可以纠正的.我们可以纠正的.
Well, now, we can correct that. We can correct that.
沙琳.我们还有的是时间,不是吗?
Charlene. We still have plenty of time, don't we?
和3天直到圣诞节...
With less than three days to go until Christmas...
...你现在没有办法让你定额.
...you now have no way of making your quota.
我想你知道那意味着什么.
And I think you know what that means.
三次.
Strike three.
听着,我也不很高兴得说,但是...
Look, it gives me no great pleasure to have to say this, but...
嗯,事实上,我开玩笑,这是个很棒的一刻!
Well, actually, who am I kidding, this is a fantastic moment for me!
你被解雇了.
You're fired.
嘿,fred,那是利昂.是22nd了.这是你的大日子,巴迪!
Hey, Fred, it's Leon. It's the 22nd. This is your big day, buddy!
这50万的!给我回电话.来吧.
Get that 50 G's in my hands! Call me back. Let's do this.
我觉得这个吧.我不希望我弟弟会成功.
And I feel this way all the time. It's not like I didn't want my brother to succeed.
我们很近了.我是说,我们上下铺.
We were very close growing up. I mean, we shared bunk beds.
巡回乐队管理员,他是我的,以前我安培.
He was my roadie, used to carry my amps.
我妈妈总是告诉我,我的孩子
And my mother always told me, since I was a little kid:
你会支持你哥哥.那是我的工作.
"You're gonna support your brother." And so that was gonna be my job.
然后洛奇出来,事情变了,你知道吗?
And then Rocky came out, and things changed, you know?
我是第一个人排队.我是说,我.
I was the first guy in line. I mean, I was there.
当洛基我出来...
And then when Rocky III came out...
...我开始怀疑谁是弗兰克硬气,你知道吗?
...I was starting to wonder who Frank Stallone was, you know?
是,比如,窃取身份.
It was, like, identity theft.
你兰博和你在洛基...
You're fighting Rambo and you're fighting Rocky...
...然后把他们围好让你来了.
...and trying to keep them at bay so you can get you to come through.
嗯,总之,我想谢谢你们听.
Well, anyway, I wanna thank you guys for listening.
我感觉好来.我喜欢这里.
I feel good coming here. I like it here.
好.谢谢分享,弗兰克.
Wonderful. Thanks for sharing, Frank.
好的.现在,我们去吧.
Okay. Now, I think we go to Roger.
我有些东西我想谈谈如果...
I actually have some things I'd like to talk about if...
好吧,你要排队.
Okay, you're just gonna have to wait your turn.
罗杰等,我们没有把他上次,那我们去吧.
Roger's been waiting, and we didn't get to him last time, so we'll go to Roger.
-我有很多东西的,是的...-我很感激.在收到.
- I have a lot of stuff boiling now, so... - I appreciate that. After Roger.
-好的.-罗杰?
- Okay. - Roger?
我是罗杰,我是个正在恢复的.
I'm Roger, I'm a recovering sibling.
嗨,收到.
Hi, Roger.
我哥哥是总统.
My brother's Bill Clinton.
我弟弟是美国总统.
My brother was the president of the United States.
你知道,我讨厌的电视频道...
You know, I was flipping through the channels on the TV...
...在历史频道是州的地址从1993年.
...and on the History Channel was the State of the Union Address from 1993.
当我们离开白宫,我以为…恢复.
When we left the White House, I thought it was gonna be the first step to recovery.
但,我开始哭了.
But no, I started to cry again.
我只是不知道我,你知道,能完全恢复了.
And I just don't know if I'm ever, you know, gonna be able to fully recover now.
也许是个地方我可以的,我们是怎么了.
Maybe that's a place where I could jump in, share what's going on with me.
-你是谁?-fred.
- Who are you? - I'm Fred.
-嗨,fred.-嗨.
- Hi, Fred. - Hi.
去吧.要转弯了?
Go ahead. Would you like to take a turn now?
-我叫弗雷德的圣诞老人.-嗨,fred.
- My name is Fred Claus. - Hi, Fred.
嗨.
Hi.
我是圣诞老人的哥哥.
I'm Santa Claus' brother.
我有很多事情了.
And I got a lot of stuff going on because of it.
有很多东西...有很多汁里了.
There's a lot of things... There's a lot of juice in the tank over it.
-了...-这是玩笑吗?
- And... - Is this a joke to you?
-stephen,对了.-嗨,stephen.
- Stephen, by the way. - Hi, Stephen.
嘿,伙计们,怎么了?
Hey, guys, what's up?
我是说,因为这不好玩了成员.
I mean, because this isn't funny to all of us here in the group.
好吧,这是非常严重的.
Okay, this is very serious to us.
我感觉很不舒服你从哪儿来的.
And I'm feeling very uncomfortable with where you're coming from.
等等,stephen...
Wait, Stephen...
...也许他,他弟弟是圣诞老人.
...maybe to him, his brother is Santa Claus.
觉得我哥哥圣诞老人.
Feel like my brother's Santa Claus.
但我觉得我哥哥圣诞老人因为我哥哥是圣诞老人.
But I feel like my brother's Santa Claus because my brother really is Santa Claus.
好吧,够了,好!你和我有问题!
All right, that's enough, all right! You and I got a problem!
stephen,放松,放松.好的.stephen,放松.
Stephen, easy, easy. All right. Stephen, easy.
这不是亚历克,好吗?
That's not Alec, okay?
别看我,看看他.
Don't look at me, look at him.
这不是艾力克.
That's not Alec.
我不是亚历克,你知道我的意思吗?
I'm not Alec, you know what I mean?
好吧,我们踩了.
All right, let's stomp it out.
-艾力克.-亚历克不会听到的.
- It's not Alec. - Alec's not gonna hear.
他会的...?
How's he gonna...?
-艾力克.-好吧,这不是艾力克.
- That's not Alec. - Okay, that's not Alec.
-阿!-阿!
- That's not Alec! - That's not Alec!
-阿!-好!
- That's not Alec! - All right!
现在你有alec注意,stephen,你要告诉他吗?
Now that you've got Alec's attention, Stephen, what do you wanna tell him?
stephen,我知道你是从哪里来的...
Stephen, I think I know where you're coming from...
...因为我以前真的,是对我弟弟.
...because I used to be really, really angry with my brother.
我不想成为第一个兄弟,尤其是一辈子.
I didn't want to become first brother, especially for the rest of my life.
我不能控制我的美国总统.
I couldn't control being brother of the president of the United States.
但我可以控制被billclinton兄弟.
But I could control being Bill Clinton's brother.
我决定了,即使我可以把房子...
And I made the decision, even though I could have brought the house down...
...我决定了,我的兄弟...
...I made the decision that, for the love of my brother...
...而我的名字...
...and for the love of my family name...
...我会不择手段的...
...that I was gonna do whatever it took...
...因为我爱我弟弟...
...because I loved my brother...
...我总是能给我哥哥.我有.
...and I was always gonna be there for my brother. And I have been.
你知道吗?
And you know what?
你也是.
You can be too.
旅行专家吗?
The Travel Experts?
是的.我要去北极的,比如,今晚.
Yeah. I need to get to the North Pole right away, like, tonight.
是的,我有50美元,5000现金说我不是开玩笑.
Yeah, I got $50,000 in cash that says I'm not kidding.
-哦,北极!北极的.-北极吗?
- Oh, North Pole! North Pole. - North Pole is there?
你的行程次数,谢谢!
Safe journeys to you, and thank you!
威利,收集所有的精灵和的工作室了.我们走.
Willie, gather all the elves and meet me in the Workshop right now. Let's go.
听着,伙计们...
Look, guys...
...我们得多礼物我们在接下来的10小时.
...we gotta make as many presents as we can in the next 10 hours.
fred,是圣诞夜.
Fred, it's Christmas Eve.
这不可能.我们建那么多的玩具了.
It's impossible. We just can't build that many toys in that time.
规则说每个孩子的玩具.
The rule says that every kid gets a toy.
那么,什么最让玩具?一个男孩一个女孩.
So, what would be the easiest toy to make? One for boys and one for girls.
-球棒.-呼拉圈.
- A baseball bat. - A Hula-Hoop.
嗯,棒球和hula-hoops是,那么.
Well, baseball bats and Hula-Hoops it is, then.
charlene,你认为我们能多给我们配额?
Charlene, do you think it's possible we can make enough gifts to meet our quota?
棒球,输了4秒, 55...
Baseball bats, lose four seconds, 55...
是的,这是有可能的.
Yeah, it is possible.
是,但是,fred,那不是孩子了.
It is, but, Fred, that's not what the kids asked for.
是的,但重要的是这孩子的玩具.
Yeah, but all that matters is that each of the kids get a toy.
他们有他们可以打开他们早上醒来了.
That they have something that they can open when they wake up in the morning.
最重要的是,他们都知道有人想他们.
Most importantly, they all know there's somebody who's thinking about them.
你们从没想过圣诞.
You guys have never missed a Christmas before.
如果你们要走了...
If you guys are gonna go out this year...
...你要走了.
...you're gonna go out trying.
好的.我们到了.
Okay. We're on it.
-我从没见过他...-因为他是…..
- I've never seen him... - That's because he's...
...扔他出去了.-没有.
...thrown his back out. - No.
-嘿,annette,你好吗?-fred.
- Hey, Annette, how you doing? - Fred.
nick,我想我们会成功的.我在工作室精灵做礼物.
Nick, I think we're gonna make it. I got elves in the Workshop making presents.
我们也,但我想我们能成功.
We're cutting corners, but I think we can make it.
你还能拯救了圣诞节.我们没有时间了.
You'll still be able to save Christmas. We don't have a lot of time.
那不可能.他不能继续他的体重.
That's impossible. The man can hardly carry his own weight.
我动不了.
I can't move.
我不能,fred.
I can't, Fred.
你能做到的.是圣诞节,快点.
You can do it. It's Christmas, come on.
-孩子们,靠我们.-哦,孩子,我希望我可以.
- The kids are out there, counting on us. - Oh, boy, I wish I could.
威利,这是你的大日子.这是你的夜晚,伙计.
Willie, this is your big night. This is your big night, pal.
你会送礼物.威利能.
You're gonna deliver the presents. Willie can.
不,fred,我不能.
No, Fred, I can't.
当然可以.你很不错那雪橇.
Of course you can. You're great on that sleigh.
不,不,你不明白.我做不到.这是规矩.
No, no, you don't understand. I can't do it. There's a rule.
只有一个圣诞老人给的礼物.
Only a Claus can deliver the presents.
你们让我单独跟我弟弟来了吗?
Do you guys mind giving me just a moment alone with my brother here?
是的.
Yeah.
我做不到,尼克.我想你知道.
I can't do that, Nick. I think you know that.
我做不到.我不喜欢坐飞机...
I'm not capable. I'm not even comfortable flying...
...或是一个乘客,让人想飞雪橇.
...or being a passenger, let alone trying to fly the sleigh.
-我不知道我周围驯鹿...-嘿,fred.
- I don't know my way around reindeer... - Hey, Fred.
没关系.
It's all right.
太荒谬了别人的期望.不.
It's ridiculous for anybody to expect that kind of thing. No.
你不能这么做.你不能.
You can't do that. You can't.
太大了.相信我,我知道.
It's too huge. Believe me, I know.
我不会让你这么做,fred.
And I would never ask you to do that, Fred.
没关系.
It's all right.
没什么.
It is all right.
nick,有一件事一直在我已经.
Nick, there's been one thing that's been eating at me since I've been here.
那naughty-nice名单了?
That Naughty-Nice List that you got?
没有淘气的孩子,尼克.
There's no naughty kids, Nick.
他们都是好孩子.
They're all good kids.
但有些害怕.
But some of them are scared.
而他们不想听的.
And some of them don't feel listened to.
他们有一些很难了.
Some of them had some pretty tough breaks too.
每个孩子都该在圣诞礼物.
But every kid deserves a present on Christmas.
是的.
Yeah.
亚洲,非洲加上,加上欧洲,北美,南美.
Africa plus Asia, plus Europe, North America, South America.
很接近了.
It's gonna be close.
我们走,人们!我们跟上节奏!
Let's go, people! Let's pick up the pace!
红fred已进入大楼.重复,红fred已进入大楼.
Red Fred has entered the building. I repeat, Red Fred has entered the building.
威利,我们走.
Willie, let's go.
发生什么吗?小精灵.你不能信任他们!
What the heck's going on around here? Little elves. You can't trust them at all!
小的.
The little tiny people.
装备不错.怎么你以为你在干什么?
Nice outfit. What the heck do you think you're doing?
-送的礼物.-哦,不.
- Delivering presents. - Oh, no.
圣诞老人是唯一能做到.
Santa is the only one who can deliver.
只有一个圣诞老人能送礼物是克劳斯.
Only a Claus can deliver presents and that is a Claus.
如果你认为我会让你侥幸逃脱,你错了.
If you think I'm gonna let you get away with this, you are sadly mistaken.
如果你不闪开的雪橇3秒...
If you don't get out of the way of this sleigh in three seconds...
...我会幸福在北极.
...I'll be the happiest guy in the North Pole.
你没这个胆量.
You don't have the guts.
好的.
Okay.
三...
Three...
...两个...
...two...
-willie,我怎么做吗?-说啊.
- Willie, how do I do this? - Just say "ho."
-好,弗莱德!漂亮的关于缰绳!-怎么了?
- Good, Fred! Nice firm grip on those reins! - What's happening now?
放松缰绳,我们得把这个东西!告诉那些人去!
Snap those reins, we gotta get this thing in the air! Tell the guys to get up!
起来,起来,起来!
Get up, get up, get up!
去你的!是,弗莱德!我们走!
There you go! You got it, Fred! We're going up!
-你在圣诞老人的雪橇!-我们在飞.出了什么事吗?
- You're flying Santa's sleigh! - We're flying. Now what's happening?
-屋顶的.-我做不到!
- Watch the roof there. - I can't do it!
给我,我怎么驾驶这玩意?
Do it to me, how do I steer this thing?
我们走!你得把我拉上去,弗莱德!
We wanna go up! So you gotta pull up on the reins there, Fred!
好的.
Okay.
圣诞节,收到?
Christmas One, do you copy?
北极的,这是圣诞节了.收到.我们听得很清楚.
North Pole, this is Christmas One. We copy. We hear you loud and clear.
60秒的着陆,北极的.
Sixty seconds and counting for a landing, North Pole.
好吧,我们有10个小时,fred.
Okay, we've got 10 hours, Fred.
我们要做送5点38北极的.
We need to be done delivering by 5:38 a.m. North Pole time.
这是日出,那游戏结束了.
That's sunrise, and that's game over.
在这,是..
Going down this thing here, it's...
会有点痛,不是吗?
It's gonna hurt a bit, isn't it?
我不会骗你.这是tickle.
I'm not gonna lie to you. It ain't gonna tickle.
哦,还有一件事,你都吃饼干.
Oh, and one more thing, make sure you eat all the cookies.
-痛别人的-我明白了.
- It hurts people's feelings if you don't. - I got it.
头12度到伦敦.
Head 12 degrees north into London.
北极的,这是圣诞节了.我们正12度到伦敦.
North Pole, this is Christmas One. We're heading 12 degrees north into London.
stephenwesleyharding.
Stephen Harding.
anna-marie歌利子弹撞到了骨头.
Anna-Marie Gormley.
好了.
Done.
艾玛的.
Emma Short.
我们会回到这里的.
We'll come back to this neighborhood later.
20度达拉斯lubbock的冲过去.
Go 20 degrees past Dallas towards Lubbock.
收到,北极的.
Roger that, North Pole.
圣诞节,你要从one-zero-niner了.
Christmas One, take your heading off one-zero-niner.
fred,fred,弗莱德!
Fred, Fred, Fred!
-,rudolph!-你确定你从来没干过吗?
- Shake it off, Rudolph! - You sure you've never done this?
你像个绝对专业让很多错误.
You're driving like an absolute pro who makes a lot of mistakes.
哦,没关系.好,好,友好.圣诞快乐.圣诞快乐.
Oh, it's okay. Friendly, friendly, friendly. Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
凯瑟琳蒂贝特了.
Katherine Tibbett.
圣诞节,转向吧70度帝国大厦.
Christmas One, veer right 70 degrees at the Empire State Building.
下一页.
Next page.
还有一份白面包的.
Have a slice of challah.
谢谢.我很感激.祝贺你.
Thank you so much. I appreciate it. Mazel tov.
那克尼什吗?让我吃这个.
And that knish? Let me just have one of these.
很难把这些美女的.你太慷慨了.
It's hard to pass these beauties up. You're too generous.
孩子.
Kid.
圣诞老人!你找到我了!
Santa! You found me!
是的,我找到你了.
Yeah, I found you.
我的孩子.
I find all the good kids.
通心粉!是你!
Macaroni! It's you!
嗨,孩子.
Hi, boy.
来吧,孩子.嗨.
Come on, boy. Hi.
slam,我要你听我的...
Slam, I want you to listen to me...
...你有什么建议一段时间,我觉得很好.
...you got some advice a while back, and I think it was a little off.
世界就是你的.
The world is what you make it.
就用你自己的.
It all starts with what you make of yourself.
我想让你相信自己,放纵的...
And I want you to believe in yourself, Slam...
...因为你有很多信仰.
...because you got a lot to believe in.
其他人就会好的...所有的了.
And the rest will all... All kind of fall into place.
-好吗?-好的.
- Okay? - Okay.
圣诞快乐,伙计.
Merry Christmas, pal.
圣诞快乐,圣诞老人.
Merry Christmas, Santa.
-哦,和圣诞老人?是的.
- Oh, and Santa? - Yeah.
这是你的钱包.
Here's your wallet back.
这是一个好的开始.
That's a good start.
我们建的动力,好吗?
Let's try and build some real momentum with that, okay?
好的.
Okay.
我想我们会成功的!
I think we're gonna make it!
圣诞节,你在吗?过来.
Christmas One, are you there? Over.
你在那里...?
Are you there...?
北极的,去吧,这是圣诞节了.
North Pole, go ahead, this is Christmas One.
祝你好运,找到你的没有蜡烛,弗雷迪.
Good luck finding your way in the dark without a candle, Freddie.
而现在,每个人都好像是有点可爱!
And as of right now, each and every one of you little adorable munchkins is fired!
回家,收拾你的.
So go home, pack up your stockings.
你是公车回elfistan或是你的.
You're taking a bus back to Elfistan or wherever the hell you're from.
北极的?
North Pole?
北极的,这是圣诞节,去吧.
North Pole, this is Christmas One, go ahead.
嘿,伙计们!
Hey, guys!
我想我们要瞎了.
I think we're flying blind up here.
当太阳升起的时候,一切都会结束.
By the time the sun rises, it will all be over.
明早见.
See you in the morning.
克莱德高射炮northcutt了...
Clyde Archibald Northcutt...
...422达西乌开车...
...422 Dashwood Drive...
...pittsburgh,宾夕法尼亚.
...Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
是的,你most-naughty名单68了.
Yeah, you made the Most-Naughty list in '68.
哦,孩子,那是个非常,调皮的.
Oh, boy, that was a very, very naughty year.
-你怎么会记得吗?-你问我是超人的.
- How could you possibly remember that? - You asked me for a Superman cape.
但我没给你个超人角,是吗?
But I didn't give you a Superman cape, did I?
-你总是戴眼镜,克莱德?-如果你认为这会改变什么...
- Did you always wear glasses, Clyde? - If you think this changes anything...
four-eyed克莱德.
Four-Eyed Clyde.
-我打赌他们叫你.-我不知道你在说...
- I bet that's what they called you. - I don't know what you're talk...
哦,你觉得那个人叫four-eyed克莱德...
Oh, and do you think that after a while of being called Four-Eyed Clyde...
...你也许有点生气?
...you maybe got a little angry?
也许你打架了.10,也许12.
Maybe you started a fight or two. Maybe 10, maybe 12.
你叫我什么.
So you asked me for something.
一个超人的.
A Superman cape.
你认为这会改变一切.
Because you thought that that was gonna change everything.
这太荒谬了.
This is ridiculous.
-所以你决定留下four-eyed克莱德?-因为克拉克・肯特戴眼镜!
- So you decide to stay Four-Eyed Clyde? - Because Clark Kent wore glasses!
但是当他变成超人...
But when he turned into Superman...
...他不需要那些该死的眼镜了,是吗?
...he didn't need those darn glasses anymore, did he?
哦,克莱德.
Oh, Clyde.
我给你的礼物,克莱德.
It was wrong of me not to give you that gift, Clyde.
我怕有个非常错误...
I fear that I had a very incorrect...
...错误的理解了...
...misguided understanding of...
...顽皮的孩子.
...naughty children.
这可能有点晚了.
So this may be a little late.
你想穿上吗?
You wanna put it on?
克劳斯,先生,我是一个45岁,我不是...
Mr. Claus, I'm a 45-year-old man, I'm not...
穿上.
Put it on.
给我.
For me.
-好的.-thattaboy了.
- Okay. - Thattaboy.
的眼镜.
Glasses off.
现在,我需要你的帮助.
Now, I need your help.
你知道你在干什么吗?
Do you know what you're doing?
1/4两点还有小熊的.
Quarter to 2 a.m. There's Ursa Minor.
我们应该在经度38.25.那是四个...
That means we should be at longitude 38.25. That's four...
左!左!
Take a left! Take a left!
我真的,需要你帮忙.
I really, really need your help.
我要你回来了,超人.
I'm gonna need you to turn the power back on, Superman.
现在,我知道你能做到的.
Now, I know that you can do this.
你得明白,我已经递交了报告.是的.
You have to understand, I've already submitted my report. It's final.
如果你不把那些礼物日出前...
If Fred doesn't deliver all those presents by sunrise...
...北极会永远关闭.没有...
...the North Pole will be shut down forever. There's nothing...
我明白.我知道.
I understand that. I do.
但是我们给他了?
But what do you say we give him his shot?
因为他不是个坏孩子的.
Because he's not a naughty kid either.
我正在努力...等等!
I'm trying to... Hold on!
看外面!看起来像大峡谷!
Just look outside! That looks like the Grand Canyon!
不是那个吗?
Isn't that it?
哦,孩子.
Oh, boy.
fred,4:15.
Fred, it's 4: 15.
听着,我要把我会尽快,好吗?
Look, I'm gonna tuck and go as fast as I can, all right?
好的,好了.
Done, done.
放松缰绳!我们得加速这个高度!
Snap the reins! We need more speed at this altitude!
-很快!说要转弯!-现在!
- Going as fast as I can! Say when to turn! - Now!
fred.
Fred.
我知道,威利,我知道.
I know, Willie, I know.
fred,我有不祥的预感.
Fred, I have a bad feeling about this.
我们成功了.
We did it.
威利.
Willie.
去!
To the snow globe!
你的哥哥都有了.
You are the best big brother anybody could ever ask for.
-佛瑞德?-我给你圣诞礼物.
- Fred? - I brought you a Christmas gift.
你怎么进来的?
How'd you get in?
我来烟囱.
I came down the chimney.
freddie,你不能仅仅穿的像父亲圣诞节...
Freddie, you can't just show up dressed like Father Christmas...
...然后到别人的烟囱.
...and come down somebody else's chimney.
事实上,我可以.我一直在做的.
Actually, I can. I've been doing that all night.
freddie,你知道吗?我开始有点担心你,现在...
Freddie, do you know what? I'm starting to get a bit worried for you, right now...
...因为你站在这里,在我卧室,穿红色的.
...because like you're standing here, in my bedroom, wearing red.
还有,你知道,这是某种禁令时间.
And, you know, it's getting like to be sort of restraining order time.
那么,你看起来有点累了,我很累.
So, you look sort of tired and I know that I'm very tired.
也许我会打电话给你,但现在我觉得你该回家了.
So maybe I'll call you later, but right now I think you should just go home.
好吗?回家吧.
All right? Just go home.
-我回家了.-你是什么?
- I am home. - You're what?
我已经放弃了我租到公寓.我会在这儿陪你.
I've given up my lease on my apartment. I'm gonna be moving in here with you.
但是听着,慢慢来.我希望你能接受这个...
But listen, take your time. I want you to digest this...
...然后处理事情.我需要一些睡眠.
...and process things. I could use a little sleep.
马上就在角落附近.我蜷缩着我们早餐角.
I'll be right out in our breakfast nook area. I'll be curled up in our breakfast nook.
当你准备好,你来找我,在我们家.
When you're ready, you come find me here at home, at our house.
不妙.我们不能睡觉时我们会跟我们一起住.
This is no good. We can't go to bed when we're arguing now that we live together.
我有个惊喜要给你.
And I got a big surprise planned for you.
哦,不,freddie,一个大惊喜,拜托.
Oh, no, Freddie, not a big surprise, please.
我想你会改变主意你看到这个.
I think you're gonna change your mind when you see this one.
freddie,很好我们要做这个?
Freddie, is it all right that we're doing this?
-这是公司的车.这是特权.-好的.
- It's a company car. It's one of the perks. - Okay.
哦,freddie,难以置信.
Oh, Freddie, it's unbelievable.
-我们在巴黎,宝贝.-我们在巴黎.
- We're in Paris, baby. - We're in Paris.
那么,你肯定想知道其他人怎么了.
So, I bet you're wondering what happened to everyone else.
那个圣诞节是最成功的.
That Christmas turned out to be one of the most successful ever.
到处都有人发现自己更满意...
People everywhere found themselves more satisfied...
...而充实的.
... and filled up than ever.
干得好,汉斯,你学到用的数据表.太棒了.
Good work, Hans, you've learned to use the spreadsheet. That's wonderful work.
所以圣诞老人雇克莱德的基础上.
So Santa hired Clyde on a consulting basis.
哦,很漂亮的毛衣,克莱德.很漂亮的毛衣.
Oh, it's a nice sweater, Clyde. Real nice sweater.
克莱德是效率相信那北极永远落后了.
Clyde's efficiency ensured that the North Pole never fell behind again.
甚至和孩子都在.
Even with every kid getting a present.
威利和莎莉发现相似和灵魂伴侣...
Willie and Charlene found out that kindred spirits and soul mates...
...经常来这些的.
... often come in all shapes and sizes.
bob和linda终于邮件.
And Bob and Linda finally got e-mail.
琳达,所有的新命令?
Linda, where are all the new orders?
我给你五分钟前!
I e-mailed you five minutes ago!
请,不要用全部大写的,好吗?
Please, do not use all caps all the time, okay?
-是的,但是...-一切都很重要.
- Yeah, but... - Not everything is that important.
爱你.
Love you.
Love you back.
你像动物.
You're jumping around like animals.
你干什么?停下.你有你...?
What are you doing? Stop. What do you got your hat on...?
你没有录像.穿的像个男人.
You don't have a video. Wear your hat like a man.
把帽子的.把你的帽子了.
Turn your hat around. Put your hat on straight.
你穿这样阻止太阳.
You wear it like this to block the sun.
当你吃,把帽子脱了.
When you're eating, take your hats off.
她是对的.尊重.脱掉帽子!
She's right. Show respect. Take off your hat!
别忘了你是说礼貌.
Don't forget "man" is also in the word "manners."
集合一个小组的圣歌.准备好了吗?三!
Bring it in for a team chant here. Ready? On three!
,2,三,杀了他们!
One, two, three, kill them!
fred一直监视猛.
Fred never stopped watching over Slam.
等下,放纵自己的家庭.
And by the next Christmas, Slam had a family of his own.
三,2,,新年快乐!
Three, two, one, happy New Year!
圣诞老人终于一个礼物他一直想要的.
And Santa Claus finally got the one present he always wanted.
他的弟弟回来.
He got his brother back.
我不会让你走的.我要你死了.我不会让你走的.
I'm not letting go. I got you in a death grip. I'm not letting go.
看!变苗条的.柑橘类水果.
Look! Slimming down. Citrus fruits.
出来,大人物.
Get out there, big guy.
更多的,你知道.
Bit more fancy, you know.
wanda,对不起.介意我带走她一下吗?
Wanda, excuse me. Mind if I take her away for a second?
哦,是的,走吧.
Oh, yeah, go right ahead.
过来,爸爸.只有你和我了.
Come here, Dad. It's just you and me now.
但是我告诉你...
But as I told you before...
...这是关于一个叫弗雷德.
... this is the story of a boy named Fred.
我喜欢wanda.我是说,她有点超出你的工作站.
I just love Wanda. I mean, she's a little bit above your station.
所以我想也许你应该算是洗心革面,你知道吗?
So I thought maybe you should just sort of clean up your act, you know?
有个新衣服开始新的一年.你的圣诞老人.
Have a great new wardrobe to start off the new year. You're a Claus.
出去.你知道,看你爸爸.他很帅.
Get out there. You know, look at your dad. He's so dapper.
别这样对我.我要积极.
Don't do it to me. I'm trying to be positive.
哦,但我是阳性.我肯定我是对的.你需要新的衣橱.
Oh, but I'm positive too. I'm positive I'm right. You need a new wardrobe.
好的.
Okay.
-新年快乐,妈妈.-新年快乐.
- Happy New Year to you, Mom. - Happy New Year.
-我爱你.-我也爱你.
- I love you. - I love you too.
差不多.
That's more like it.
怎么样了?
How about that move?